<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title></title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.thehoya.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://www.thehoya.com</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 14:56:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=4.1.18</generator>
	
	<item>
    	  <guid>urn:uuid:1335c695-cfb8-4ebb-abbd-80da344efa6b</guid>
      	  <title> TheHoya </title>
     	  <description> </description>
          <link>https://voicelabs.co</link>
          <pubDate>2017-05-24T09:44:04Z</pubDate>
   	  <enclosure url="https://d366cdbbwqnolc.cloudfront.net/progressive/skill-leadin-2.mp3?slotId=6dc1b640-30f2-11a7-1692-0e9141af46f8;adId=41" length="262172" type="audio/mpeg"/>  
	</item>
	
	
	<item>
		<title>Hunnam and Hounsou Discuss &#8216;King Arthur,&#8217; Acting</title>
		<link>http://www.thehoya.com/hunnam-and-hounsou-discuss-king-arthur-acting/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thehoya.com/hunnam-and-hounsou-discuss-king-arthur-acting/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 16:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Guide Editor]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Guide - Top]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[actors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adventure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[charlie hunnam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[directors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[djminon hounsou]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drama]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fantasy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[film]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[guy ritchie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[interview]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[king arthur]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thehoya.com/?p=23074532</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Charlie Hunnam, star of “Pacific Rim” and “Sons of Anarchy,” and Golden Globe-nominated actor Djimon Hounsou, of “Gladiator” and “Blood Diamond,” are no strangers to Hollywood action films. Most recently, Hunnam and Hounsou played the roles of Arthur and Bedivere, respectively, in the fantasy-adventure film “King Arthur: Legend of the<a class="more-link" href="http://www.thehoya.com/hunnam-and-hounsou-discuss-king-arthur-acting/">Read More</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com/hunnam-and-hounsou-discuss-king-arthur-acting/">Hunnam and Hounsou Discuss &#8216;King Arthur,&#8217; Acting</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com"></a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[

Charlie Hunnam, star of “Pacific Rim” and “Sons of Anarchy,” and Golden Globe-nominated actor Djimon Hounsou, of “Gladiator” and “Blood Diamond,” are no strangers to Hollywood action films. Most recently, Hunnam and Hounsou played the roles of Arthur and Bedivere, respectively, in the fantasy-adventure film “King Arthur: Legend of the Sword,” directed by Guy Ritchie. In anticipation of the film’s May 12 release, Hunnam and Hounsou spoke with a group of college journalists about the experience of working on the film and their perceptions of the King Arthur legend.

<strong>COLLEGE TIMES:</strong><strong> What was the most important thing you think you learned from Guy Ritchie?</strong>

HUNNAM: It’s twofold. I mean, I think, on the surface, what he taught me was the importance of having fun while you work; I tend to be pretty serious about the work I do and go in with a lot of preparation and just set about quietly executing my game plan, and Guy said, that’s all well and good, but I don’t know what we’re going to be shooting, so you better come ready to be a little bit more light on your feet … So that was a really liberating, sort of new approach for me to filmmaking.

<strong>THE GAZETTE (WESTERN UNIVERSITY): What audience do you hope the film will attract?</strong>

HUNNAM: I think the thing for me, and that Guy and I discussed a lot, was that Arthur has always historically been rendered as this very noble man who goes on a noble quest to become a noble king, but it’s sort of quite elitist in that rendering, and what we wanted to really do was make Arthur an everyman. Just somebody that everybody could relate to and that felt accessible. And one of the amazing things, the most exciting thing about film, is that it’s a universal language. So I think that people from all parts of the world and all cultures can take something from this, it’s really a universal story. Ultimately it’s about how do we become the best version of ourselves, and when we’re presented with a challenge in our lives that seems insurmountable, why do we shy away from it?

<strong>BERKLEE COLLEGE OF MUSIC: </strong><strong>Why did you both choose to be in this film?</strong>

HOUNSOU: Well, I think, for me, the story and the director, Guy Ritchie. His body of work is just, I guess, it’s quite iconic.  Obviously the story of King Arthur, it’s quite a legendary story.

HUNNAM: Yeah, same for me. Film is a director’s medium, and the input that an actor has beyond the interpretation of their character is very, very limited, so it’s essential that you really trust a director’s vision and his sensibility as a filmmaker. And, you know, obviously it’s always wonderful if there’s scenes within the film that resonate with you and speak to your vision of life or areas of life that you’re interested in exploring.

<strong>THE HOYA: King Arthur is a myth that</strong><strong> i</strong><strong>s very popular and has been told many times, and this movie is billed as an “iconoclastic” take on it. What do you think is special or unique in its telling of the story?</strong>

HUNNAM: We talk about the fact that King Arthur has been told many times, but ultimately King Arthur is one version of the telling of the hero’s journey, which is one of the archetypal stories, the three or four stories that we dress up [in] different ways that we tell over and over again, because storytelling, by nature, or historically, has been a way in which we understand the human journey. And so, having Guy Ritchie at the helm immediately makes this fresh and original and unique, because there’s nobody out there that really has that vision that he has as a filmmaker. I mean, immediately you know that it’s going to be cheeky and irreverent and fresh and unexpected and original.

<strong>THE ALESTLE (SOUTHERN ILLINOIS UNIVERSITY): Were there any similarities between your role as Arthur and as Jax in “Sons of Anarchy”</strong><strong>?</strong>

HUNNAM: They’re both sort of ordinary men who are called to do extraordinary things — and I was reading a quote the other day, that there are no great men, just ordinary men that are called to greatness through circumstance, and that seems to be a narrative that I’m drawn to over and over again.  That the idea of, you know, we all just have these great doubts about our abilities in life, and you never know unless you try. And both of those men are forced into a situation through their birthright, through the environment that they were born into and these families that they come from, called to these really lofty destinies, neither of which they chose for themselves and both of which want to deny it, but as we all know, denying one’s destiny’s not that simple.

<strong>THE PEAK (SIMON FRASIER UNIVERSITY): Being a Guy Ritchie film, I know there’s going to be a lot of humor in it, but how much of the humor in the film is in the script and how much was left to you guys to add into the movie?</strong>

HOUNSOU: Well, I did not see much humor in the script. I think that the humor sort of like, came organically as we were interacting with Guy Ritchie. As a director I think that most of his work is to see what looks funny.

HUNNAM: Yeah, Guy Ritchie’s not much of a preparation man; he really has an extraordinary ability to work in real time, and so the script for Guy is really just a blueprint and the whole thing’s going to come alive on the day, which is why he’s very specific about the team he puts together, because he wants some like-minded people who he feels have the ability to contribute to the process. It’s why it’s exciting for Djimon and I — it’s a really rich collaboration working with Guy, and like Djimon said, a lot of that humor came from us shooting the scene a couple of times as scripted, and then saying well, we can do better, let’s throw some jokes in, and us starting to banter around …  Before you know it, the scene in real time has transformed from something that was the basic movements of what the scene needed to be, and then we sort of render it and color it in in real time.<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com/hunnam-and-hounsou-discuss-king-arthur-acting/">Hunnam and Hounsou Discuss &#8216;King Arthur,&#8217; Acting</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com"></a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thehoya.com/hunnam-and-hounsou-discuss-king-arthur-acting/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Movies Turning 10</title>
		<link>http://www.thehoya.com/movies-turning-10/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thehoya.com/movies-turning-10/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 13:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Guide Editor]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Summer Highlights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Guide]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[10]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[anniversary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[film]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[movie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ratatouille]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stardust]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thehoya.com/?p=23074674</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>“Juno” Directed by Jason Reitman &#124; Starring Ellen Page and Michael Cera Witty, moving and unapologetic, the premiere of “Juno” at the 2007 Toronto International Film Festival was met with a standing ovation. From there, “Juno” received its fair share of praise, winning an Oscar for Diablo Cody’s original screenplay<a class="more-link" href="http://www.thehoya.com/movies-turning-10/">Read More</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com/movies-turning-10/">Movies Turning 10</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com"></a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<strong>“Juno”</strong>

Directed by Jason Reitman | Starring Ellen Page and Michael Cera

Witty, moving and unapologetic, the premiere of “Juno” at the 2007 Toronto International Film Festival was met with a standing ovation. From there, “Juno” received its fair share of praise, winning an Oscar for Diablo Cody’s original screenplay and topping famed film critic Roger Ebert’s annual list of best movies. The comedy-drama’s honest treatment of the titular protagonist’s teenage pregnancy and the stellar performances from the cast transformed the film’s coming-of-age narrative into a fresh, bold take on adulthood and parenthood.

For another 2007 comedy, see “Superbad.”

<strong>“Ratatouille”</strong>

Directed by Brad Bird | Starring Patton Oswalt and Ian Holm

With its unlikely rodent hero and visually stunning depictions of Paris and French cuisine, “Ratatouille” was a worthy addition to Pixar’s canon of films. The dynamic combo of idealistic rat Remy, who has ambitions of haute cuisine, and awkward young man Linguini, who is trying his best to get by, keeps audiences of all ages entertained. With its commentary on the nature of art, and the kind of people who create or critique it, “Ratatouille” never goes for the cheap laugh, delivering its narrative with sincerity and warmth.

For another 2007 animated features, see “Bee Movie.”

<strong>“There Will Be Blood”</strong>

Directed by Paul Thomas Anderson | Starring Daniel Day-Lewis and Paul Dano



An epic historical drama, Paul Thomas Anderson’s “There Will Be Blood” won widespread critical acclaim as one of the greatest films of the 2000s. Inspired by Upton Sinclair’s “Oil!,” the film details the merciless quest of a silver miner for wealth during California’s oil boom. The ruthless prospector, and his gradual moral decay, is played masterfully by Daniel Day-Lewis, who would go on to win a litany of accolades for the role.

For another 2007 historical thriller, see “No Country for Old Men.”

<strong>“Hairspray”</strong>

Directed by Adam Shankman | Starring Nikki Blonsky and John Travolta



Based off the 2002 stage musical that was in turn based off the 1988 comedy film, “Hairspray” had no shortage of source material to work from. Instead, director Adam Shankman and writer Leslie Dixon refreshed the story, adding a millennial patina to the film’s retro premise and handling serious issues like segregation with maturity. Starring an exuberant Nikki Blonsky in her breakout role as Tracy Turnblad, a plump teenager who aspires to local teen dance show stardom, the film’s ensemble cast includes heavy-hitters like John Travolta, Michelle Pfeiffer, Christopher Walken, Amanda Bynes, James Marsden, Queen Latifah and Zac Efron.

For another 2007 live-action musical, see “Across the Universe.”

<strong>“Stardust”</strong>

Directed by Matthew Vaughn | Starring Claire Danes and Charlie Cox

A thrilling fantasy adventure, Matthew Vaughn’s “Stardust” is spellbinding and captivating. Adapted from Neil Gaiman’s 1999 novel of the same name, the film follows Tristan, a young man from the fictional English village of Wall. As Tristan journeys into the bordering fantasy kingdom of Stormhold to collect a fallen star for his crush, he is surprised to discover the star is a young woman. As the pair return to Wall, the audience is introduced to a whimsical cast of well-developed supporting characters and an enthralling, magical world.

For another 2007 romance, see “Atonement.”<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com/movies-turning-10/">Movies Turning 10</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com"></a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thehoya.com/movies-turning-10/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Summertime in DC</title>
		<link>http://www.thehoya.com/summertime-in-d-c/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thehoya.com/summertime-in-d-c/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 13:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Guide Editor]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Summer Highlights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Guide]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[concrts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[festivals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[film]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[museums]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[restaurants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[summer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[summertime]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thehoya.com/?p=23074689</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Museums and Exhibits Across the District Concerts and Festivals: Editor's Picks A Breath of Fresh Air: Nature Near D.C. FILM Upcoming Movie Releases Best Summer Movies Movies Turning 10! FOOD Tastes of the World: International Cuisines in D.C. Hottest D.C. Summer Eats MUSIC Recent Album Releases Upcoming Releases guide's Summer<a class="more-link" href="http://www.thehoya.com/summertime-in-d-c/">Read More</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com/summertime-in-d-c/">Summertime in DC</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com"></a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[

<a href="http://www.thehoya.com/museum-exhibits-across-the-district/"><em>Museums and Exhibits Across the District</em></a>

<a href="http://www.thehoya.com/concerts-and-festivals-editors-picks/"><em>Concerts and Festivals: Editor's Picks</em></a>

<a href="http://www.thehoya.com/a-breath-of-fresh-air-nature-near-dc/"><em>A Breath of Fresh Air: Nature Near D.C.</em></a>

<strong>FILM</strong>

<a href="http://www.thehoya.com/upcoming-movie-releases/"><em>Upcoming Movie Releases</em></a>

<a href="http://www.thehoya.com/best-summer-movies/"><i>Best Summer Movies</i></a>

<a href="http://www.thehoya.com/movies-turning-10/"><em>Movies Turning 10!</em></a>

<strong>FOOD</strong>

<a href="http://www.thehoya.com/tastes-of-the-world-international-cuisines-in-dc/"><em>Tastes of the World: International Cuisines in D.C.</em></a>

<a href="http://www.thehoya.com/hottest-d-c-summer-eats/"><em>Hottest D.C. Summer Eats</em></a>

<strong>MUSIC</strong>

<a href="http://www.thehoya.com/recent-album-releases/"><em>Recent Album Releases</em></a>

<a href="http://www.thehoya.com/upcoming-releases/"><em>Upcoming Releases</em></a>

<i><a href="https://open.spotify.com/user/thehoyaguide/playlist/5JhxyUX24A4TXRvgvMsrVa">guide's Summer Playlist</a></i>

https://open.spotify.com/user/thehoyaguide/playlist/5JhxyUX24A4TXRvgvMsrVa

&nbsp;<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com/summertime-in-d-c/">Summertime in DC</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com"></a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thehoya.com/summertime-in-d-c/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	
	
	<item>
    	  <guid>urn:uuid:1335c695-cfb8-4ebb-abbd-80da344efa6b</guid>
      	  <title> TheHoya </title>
     	  <description> </description>
          <link>https://voicelabs.co</link>
          <pubDate>2017-05-24T09:44:04Z</pubDate>
   	  <enclosure url="https://d366cdbbwqnolc.cloudfront.net/espn/WCF-generic.mp3?slotId=9d21ce10-34db-11a7-1692-0e9141af46f8;adId=66" length="602996" type="audio/mpeg"/> 
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>TV Shows To Catch This Summer</title>
		<link>http://www.thehoya.com/tv-shows-to-catch-this-summer/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thehoya.com/tv-shows-to-catch-this-summer/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 13:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Guide Editor]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Summer Highlights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Guide]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[comedy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drama]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[game of thrones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[master of none]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Netflix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[orphan black]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Show]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[summer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tv]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[watch]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thehoya.com/?p=23074682</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>‘Master of None’ When “Master of None” premiered on Netflix in 2015, viewers of the show were instantly captivated by its stunning authenticity and witty humor, lauding comedian Aziz Ansari for writing such a thoughtful and culturally relevant script. The show addresses the personal issues faced by its main character,<a class="more-link" href="http://www.thehoya.com/tv-shows-to-catch-this-summer/">Read More</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com/tv-shows-to-catch-this-summer/">TV Shows To Catch This Summer</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com"></a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<em>‘Master of None’</em>

When “Master of None” premiered on Netflix in 2015, viewers of the show were instantly captivated by its stunning authenticity and witty humor, lauding comedian Aziz Ansari for writing such a thoughtful and culturally relevant script. The show addresses the personal issues faced by its main character, Dev — played by Ansari — who struggles with his identity as the son of immigrants, a millennial searching for employment and simply as a single man trying to navigate a rapidly changing dating scene.



The second season of “Master of None” premiered May 12 on Netflix. Composed of 10 episodes, the season heads in a more developed direction, highlighting new subject matter as well as continuing to employ different visual elements to provide fans with a distinctive and compelling viewing experience. Although a third season has yet to be confirmed, season two of “Master of None” provides audiences with enough clever humor and insight to last the summer.

<em>‘Game of Thrones’</em>



Perhaps the most anticipated show of the summer, HBO’s “Game of Thrones” returns for its seventh — and penultimate — season July 16. Although returning for only seven episodes, as opposed to the usual 10 per season, “Game of Thrones” has legions of fans anticipating its summer premiere date, having garnered a significant following since its debut in 2011. Joining fan-favorite cast members Emilia Clarke, Kit Harington and Peter Dinklage are newcomers Jim Broadbent and Tom Hopper, playing Archmaester Marwyn and Dickon Tarly, respectively — characters who will certainly bring their fair share of drama to the fantastical world of Westeros.

The Emmy Award-winning series not only plans to expand its cast, but also promises to deliver on and resolve storylines that began in the show’s first season, as it slowly brings characters together for a final battle for power. With its gifted cast, critically acclaimed script and beloved story, “Game of Thrones” is certainly one of the top TV picks for this summer.

<em>‘Orange Is the New Black’</em>



After ending on a dramatic cliffhanger last season, Netflix’s critically acclaimed hit series “Orange Is the New Black” is back, picking up right where the season four finale left off. After the tragic death of one of their own, the prisoners of Litchfield Prison are ready to revolt, angry at the actions of their oppressors. The fifth season, which will take course over three drama-filled days at the prison, will show new sides of the characters that fans have come to love, bringing a greater level of depth to the already well-developed show.

Although no new actors are set to be introduced this season, long-standing cast member Laura Prepon — who plays the mysterious Alex Vause — will direct the 10th episode, marking her highly anticipated directorial debut. The fifth season, which will span 13 episodes in total, will be available on Netflix starting June 9, and the sixth and seventh seasons have already been confirmed by producers.

<em>‘Twin Peaks’</em>



ABC’s cult classic “Twin Peaks” is considered one of the best television programs of the 1990s. The crime drama follows the story of FBI agent Dale Cooper, played by Kyle MacLachlan, as he delves into a murder investigation in the mysterious town Twin Peaks, Wash.. This year, Showtime will continue the surreal story of “Twin Peaks” in “Twin Peaks: The Return,” as Cooper makes his long-awaited return to the town.

Although few details have been revealed about the upcoming season, “Twin Peaks: The Return” promises to bring the same sense of surrealism and mystery that established the original as one of the most groundbreaking series of its time. Fans of “Twin Peaks” will enjoy watching the return of MacLachlan and a majority of the other original cast members. Series creators David Lynch and Mark Frost and composer Angelo Badalamenti have also returned to work on the new season. A number of new actors will make appearances this season as well, including Laura Dern, Naomi Watts and Michael Cera.

<em>‘Unbreakable Kimmy Schmidt’</em>



“Unbreakable Kimmy Schmidt” is one of Netflix’s most successful shows to date. Premiering in 2015, the hilarious sitcom instantly attracted a strong viewership with its offbeat story and stellar screenplay. The show follows the misadventures of Kimmy Schmidt, a comically optimistic cult survivor played by Ellie Kemper, as she navigates the big city and encounters a host of quirky friends. The series has consistently been a critical favorite — two seasons in, “Unbreakable Kimmy Schmidt” has garnered 11 Emmy Award nominations — and earned its renewal for a third season last year.

Premiering today on Netflix, season three of “Kimmy Schmidt” will follow the titular character as she heads off on her next great adventure: college, sure to be a source of hysterical mishaps. Viewers can also look forward to the exciting additions of new cast members, such as Laura Dern and Maya Rudolph, as well as the returns of fan-favorite actors Tituss Burgess and Jane Krakowski, masters of comedic timing.

<em>‘Orphan Black’</em>



The fifth and final season of “Orphan Black” will premiere June 10 on BBC America, promising to deliver an action-packed conclusion to the sci-fi series that first premiered in 2013. The Canadian dystopian drama follows the story of Sarah Manning — played by the Emmy Award-winning Tatiana Maslany — a con artist living in a dark futuristic world where she is one of a number of clones, each portrayed by Maslany.

Over the course of the series, the versatile actress has played nearly a dozen different roles, acting as both a star and supporting actress all in one. As she heads into her final season, Maslany — now also a producer on the show — hopes to continue the show’s legacy of brilliant acting and complex storytelling. Viewers can expect to see old characters — and clones — return, and should, of course, plan for a few plot twists along the way.<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com/tv-shows-to-catch-this-summer/">TV Shows To Catch This Summer</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com"></a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thehoya.com/tv-shows-to-catch-this-summer/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Upcoming Movie Releases</title>
		<link>http://www.thehoya.com/upcoming-movie-releases/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thehoya.com/upcoming-movie-releases/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 13:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Guide Editor]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Summer Highlights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Guide]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beguiled]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dunkirk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marvel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[michael keaton]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[movies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nolan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spiderman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[upcoming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wonder woman]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thehoya.com/?p=23074669</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Wonder Woman &#124; JUNE 2 Directed by Patty Jenkins &#124; Starring Gal Gadot and Chris Pine Israeli actress Gal Gadot made her on-screen debut as Wonder Woman in “Batman v. Superman: Dawn of Justice” in 2016. Despite the film’s poor critical reception, Gadot was highly praised for her standout portrayal<a class="more-link" href="http://www.thehoya.com/upcoming-movie-releases/">Read More</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com/upcoming-movie-releases/">Upcoming Movie Releases</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com"></a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<strong>Wonder Woman </strong>| JUNE 2

Directed by Patty Jenkins | Starring Gal Gadot and Chris Pine



Israeli actress Gal Gadot made her on-screen debut as Wonder Woman in “Batman v. Superman: Dawn of Justice” in 2016. Despite the film’s poor critical reception, Gadot was highly praised for her standout portrayal of the fierce superheroine, leaving fans of DC Comics eagerly awaiting her standalone film: “Wonder Woman,” set to premiere June 2. “Wonder Woman” is an epic origin story that will follow the Amazonian princess warrior Diana Prince as she leaves her reclusive island of Themyscira to try to stop World War I, discovering her heroic identity along the way. Gadot stars alongside Chris Pine, who plays Steve Trevor, the American pilot who convinces Diana to leave her home to save the outside world from ruin — and, ultimately, fulfill her destiny as Wonder Woman.

<strong>THE BEGUILED </strong>| JUNE 23

Directed by Sofia Coppola | Starring Colin Farrell and Nicole Kidman



In 1971, Clint Eastwood and Geraldine Page starred in “The Beguiled,” a drama based on Thomas P. Cullinan’s 1966 Southern Gothic novel of the same name. Although the film was well-received by critics, it remained largely unrecognized in the United States — until this year. On June 23, audiences across the country will be able to relive all of the sinister drama and mystery of the original in a remake of the film written and directed by Sofia Coppola. “The Beguiled” takes place during the Civil War telling the story of an injured soldier, played by Colin Farrell, who arrives at a women’s boarding school in the South. As the women of the school, played by Nicole Kidman, Kirsten Dunst and Elle Fanning, become increasingly infatuated with the soldier, the school’s tense atmosphere of sexual repression and secrecy threatens to explode in violence and betrayal.

<strong>SPIDER-MAN: HOMECOMING </strong>| JULY 7

Directed by Jon Watts | Starring Tom Holland and Michael Keaton

In any given year, a good portion of new cinematic releases are remakes of older films, and superhero franchises are especially well-known for being given the Hollywood reset treatment. This year, for example, Marvel Studios will release “Spider-Man: Homecoming,” with rising star Tom Holland in the lead role of Peter Parker. Holland is the third actor to play Spider-Man in roughly a decade and has big shoes to fill — Tobey Maguire starred in the first “Spider-Man” in 2002, and Andrew Garfield in the 2012 reboot — yet promises to bring a fresh and youthful approach to the character. This time around, the focus of the film will be Parker’s difficulty to balance his life as a high schooler with his role as a superhero, as he faces a dangerous new threat: the villainous Vulture, to be played by Michael Keaton. Fans of the franchise will want to mark their calendars for July 7 — the film’s premiere date — and see for themselves whether or not the new series lives up to its expectations.

<strong>DUNKIRK </strong>| JULY 21

Directed by Christopher Nolan | Starring Tom Hardy and Mike Rylance



In a summer of comedies and superhero blockbusters, Christopher Nolan’s “Dunkirk” stands out as a powerful must-see film, sure to move audiences with its compelling wartime story. Set for release July 21, the film is about the Dunkirk evacuation of World War II — an event that shaped the course of the 20th century, particularly for the British. Nolan chose to tell the story through a threefold perspective, looking at the military operative through land, air and sea, without focusing on one specific protagonist or character arc. In fact, “Dunkirk” develops much of its story through its score and cinematography, with little conversation between characters, adding to its heightened sense of suspense and tension. Its male-dominated cast includes a number of high-profile actors — Tom Hardy, Mike Rylance, Cillian Murphy and Sir Kenneth Branagh — who face the challenge of bringing the dialogue-thin script to life. Given Nolan’s status as one of the most accomplished filmmakers of the 21st century, “Dunkirk” is widely expected to be a standout of the season, as Nolan expertly weaves a poignant human story over the backdrop of one of the most historic events of the war.

<strong>THE DARK TOWER </strong>| AUGUST 4

Directed by Nikolaj Arcel | Starring Idris Elba and

Matthew McConaughey

Although many film adaptations of Stephen King’s novels have fallen squarely in the horror genre, the latest of its kind, “The Dark Tower,” will combine elements of science fiction, fantasy and Western film. “The Dark Tower” continues King’s eight-part book series of the same name, telling the story of Roland Deschain — played by Idris Elba — a man sworn to protect the Dark Tower, the supernatural object that holds his universe together. Deschain’s mission is complicated by the arrival of the villainous Walter Padick — played by the Academy Award-winning Matthew McConaughey — a sorcerer quite literally hellbent on stopping him. With its two highly accomplished lead actors and the source text of one of the best suspense writers of all time, “The Dark Tower” promises to be one of the most thrilling watches of the summer. The film will be released in theaters Aug. 4 and a television series, also to star Elba, is currently in the works.<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com/upcoming-movie-releases/">Upcoming Movie Releases</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com"></a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thehoya.com/upcoming-movie-releases/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hottest DC Summer Eats</title>
		<link>http://www.thehoya.com/hottest-d-c-summer-eats/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thehoya.com/hottest-d-c-summer-eats/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 13:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Guide Editor]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Summer Highlights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Guide]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bubble tea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[halal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[insomnia cookies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[isabella eatery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[siren]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tysons galleria]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thehoya.com/?p=23074658</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>New Food Spots Ladurée Ladurée is a luxury French bakery best recognized for its colorful double-decker macarons and handmade sweets. The bakery first opened its doors in 1862 and has since expanded on a global level, with 11 locations in the United States — including its recent opening in Georgetown.<a class="more-link" href="http://www.thehoya.com/hottest-d-c-summer-eats/">Read More</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com/hottest-d-c-summer-eats/">Hottest DC Summer Eats</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com"></a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<span style="text-decoration: underline;">New Food Spots</span>

<strong>Ladurée</strong>



Ladurée is a luxury French bakery best recognized for its colorful double-decker macarons and handmade sweets. The bakery first opened its doors in 1862 and has since expanded on a global level, with 11 locations in the United States — including its recent opening in Georgetown. Located on M Street, the restaurant serves breakfast, brunch, lunch, afternoon tea, coffee and aperitifs — alcoholic beverages served before meals, often to stimulate the appetite. Although it boasts a menu of savory dishes, Ladurée’s French pastries, homemade ice creams and chocolates are its signature specialties — all must-tries for anyone with a sweet tooth. Visitors can indulge in light desserts and drinks while enjoying the restaurant’s upscale Parisian ambience.

<strong>Waterfront Rosé Garden at Whal</strong><strong>ey’s </strong>



Raw bar and restaurant Whaley’s is one of the hottest spots for Washington, D.C. residents to get their seafood fix. Recently, the popular venue opened up its very own rosé garden: a waterfront bar serving up an elegant ambience and a mouth-watering menu of snacks, cocktails, frozen drinks and, of course, 10 different varieties of rosé. Visitors to the bar are treated to stunning river views, a beachy atmosphere and luscious cold drinks, making it the perfect summertime hangout. The Rosé Garden seats up to 30 guests and is open until 10 p.m.

<strong>The Halal Guys</strong>



The Halal Guys began as a simple grab-and-go halal eatery on a street corner in Manhattan, but it has since expanded onto the popular food scene, adding locations across the country — and even internationally. The fast-casual restaurant recently opened two spots in the D.C. area — one in Dupont Circle and one in the Atlas District —  attracting customers from across the city. The Halal Guys’ most recognizable dishes are its chicken and gyro rice bowls and wraps, served with a tangy white sauce and roasted vegetables. Lines for the halal dishes may be long but are certainly worth the wait.

<strong>Siren</strong>



Belgian-American chef Robert Wiedmaier has become a staple of the D.C. food scene since opening Marcel’s, a high-end French-Belgian restaurant, in Foggy Bottom in 1999. Since then, Wiedmaier has continued to expand his presence in the area — most recently with Siren, a fine dining seafood restaurant in Logan Circle. In addition to offering its signature seafood platters, Siren serves a number of lesser-known varieties of fish, giving its food a distinctive flavor. Although certain items on the menu can be quite pricey — the Grand Plateau, a large seafood platter, is most expensive at $150  — visitors can select from more affordable options that will still ensure a deluxe eating experience.

<span style="text-decoration: underline;">Restaurants Coming Soon</span>

<strong>Kung Fu Tea</strong>



New York-based bubble tea franchise Kung Fu Tea recently made its long-awaited arrival in the greater D.C. area with locations in Rockville and Silver Spring, Md., and Mclean, Va. This summer, however, Kung Fu Tea will be even closer, as it prepares to open a new location on Wisconsin Avenue. Visitors of the bubble tea cafe are able select from a long list of drinks, including fruit- and milk-based teas, yogurts, slushies and punches, and even a variety of seasonal specialties. From there, customers can handcraft their orders, fine-tuning temperature and flavor, while also choosing from an assortment of toppings. As Kung Fu Tea continues to expand across the country, D.C. foodies will not want to miss out on the chance to have a taste.

&nbsp;

<strong>Isabella Eatery in Tyson Galleria </strong>



Restaurateur and chef Mike Isabella, well-known for his work on “Top Chef,”  has major plans to expand his base in D.C. this summer. Over the past few months, Isabella has been developing a 10-part eatery on the third floor of Tysons Galleria, one of the most popular shopping malls in the D.C. area. Isabella Eatery, which covers over 41,000 square feet, will seat over 600 patrons in its 10 dining spots. The eclectic assortment of venues include a seafood bar, sit-down Mexican and Mediterranean restaurants, a coffee shop and a casual Japanese eatery. Isabella Eatery will provide a wide variety of cuisines all under one roof, making it the go-to for foodies in D.C. this summer.

<strong>Blue Bottle Coffee</strong>



Headquartered in Oakland, Calif., Blue Bottle Coffee has become an integral part of the “new wave” of artisanal coffee shops sprawling across the country. The chain, with locations throughout the United States, boasts the freshest product — in fact, it only sells coffee within 48 hours of brewing. The company, which sells a variety of blends, emphasizes brewing coffee at just the right time — even providing patrons with a helpful “flavor timeline” to ensure the highest-quality taste. Blue Bottle Coffee will have opened three spots in D.C. by 2018 and has confirmed one of the three locations to be along Potomac Street — perfect for Georgetown students in need of a caffeine fix.

<strong>Insomnia Cookies</strong>



Although Georgetown students love Wisey’s cookies, they will certainly jump at the chance to have a taste of Insomnia Cookies this summer. With more than 90 locations nationwide, Insomnia Cookies has gained quite a loyal clientele — customers love having the bakery’s warm, gooey cookies delivered right to their door. Insomnia Cookies opened its first location in the District last year, in Adams Morgan, and plans to add two more this season, along H and O streets in Georgetown. Though the eatery specializes in warm baked goods, it will surely attract passersby with the prospect of refreshing ice cream cookie sandwiches. With locations so close to Georgetown, students may just find themselves making late-night orders — after all, the bakery delivers fresh cookies until 3 a.m.<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com/hottest-d-c-summer-eats/">Hottest DC Summer Eats</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com"></a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thehoya.com/hottest-d-c-summer-eats/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Museum Exhibits Across the District</title>
		<link>http://www.thehoya.com/museum-exhibits-across-the-district/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thehoya.com/museum-exhibits-across-the-district/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 13:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Guide Editor]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Summer Highlights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Guide]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[exhibit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[explore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gallery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[history]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kennedy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[museum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[painting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smitshonian]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thehoya.com/?p=23074548</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>“Wish Tree for Washington, D.C.” The Hirshhorn Museum and Sculpture Garden is one of D.C.’s premier art galleries, attracting millions of visitors each year with its eye-catching exhibits. In 2007, during the annual National Cherry Blossom Festival, the Hirshhorn installed “Wish Tree for Washington, D.C.,” a sculpture by Yoko Ono<a class="more-link" href="http://www.thehoya.com/museum-exhibits-across-the-district/">Read More</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com/museum-exhibits-across-the-district/">Museum Exhibits Across the District</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com"></a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<strong>“Wish Tree for Washington, D.C.”</strong>

The Hirshhorn Museum and Sculpture Garden is one of D.C.’s premier art galleries, attracting millions of visitors each year with its eye-catching exhibits. In 2007, during the annual National Cherry Blossom Festival, the Hirshhorn installed “Wish Tree for Washington, D.C.,” a sculpture by Yoko Ono aimed at promoting harmony and prosperity by having visitors write and attach “paper wishes” to the sprawling Japanese dogwood tree. Visitors have been able to attach their wishes every summer.



This June, the museum will celebrate the 10th anniversary of Ono’s “Wish Tree” with a series of performances and pieces inspired by the visionary artist. The original “Wish Tree” will be on show starting June 17, which will also see the the Washington debut of “My Mommy is Beautiful.” “My Mommy is Beautiful” is an interactive art installation by Ono that will allow participants to leave photos and keepsakes to celebrate their own mothers; it promises to be one of the Hirshhorn’s most engaging and poignant pieces of the year.

The museum will also invite visitors to observe a reinstallation of “Sky TV for Washington, D.C.” Originally created in 1966, Ono’s “Sky TV” plays a live feed of the world outside the Hirshhorn, encouraging its viewers to be more observant of their surroundings. This “Summer of Yoko Ono” concludes in September with a concert featuring Ono and performers from Washington, D.C., who will celebrate her legacy and lifetime of activism through song.

<em>“Summer of Yoko Ono” will be available for viewing at the Hirshhorn from June 17 through September Admission to the Hirshhorn is free.</em>

<strong>“Down These Mean Streets: Community and Place in Urban Photography”</strong>



Images of urban life have become prevalent across social media platforms in recent years as artists are increasingly able to provide online viewers with colorful snapshots of city life. Contemporary depictions of big cities often focus on the excitement and opportunity of the urban experience, drawing attention away from its many difficulties — particularly, in the inner city. The Smithsonian American Art Museum’s new gallery, “Down These Mean Streets: Community and Place in Urban Photography” explores the concept of city life in the late 20th century through the works of Latinx photographers, who bring raw and honest perspectives to the idealized perceptions of urban living.

The exhibit will showcase the works of 10 photographers who artfully capture the challenges of life on the streets in cities like Los Angeles and New York. Images in the exhibit reflect on issues of inequality, marginalization and the neglect of underprivileged communities, illustrating the power of the critical camera lens. Among the featured photographers are Frank Espada, an activist and documentary photographer best known for his poignant portraits of urban residents, and Oscar Castillo, who documented the Los Angeles-based Chicano movement of the 1960s, which aimed to secure civil rights for Mexican Americans.

<em> “Down These Mean Streets” is on view at the Smithsonian American Art Museum until Aug. 6.</em>

<strong>“American Visionary: John F. Kennedy’s Life and Times”</strong>

The Smithsonian American Art Museum recently unveiled its newest project, “American Visionary: John F. Kennedy’s Life and Times,” a stunning photo exhibit that celebrates the legacy of the former president, who has long been considered a symbol of national character. Although he came into office at a time of high tension and uncertainty, Kennedy was able to shape a strong and confident American public by sharing his progressive and patriotic values. The Smithsonian Museum’s latest exhibit reflects on Kennedy’s lasting legacy by highlighting his most iconic quotes and photographs, which have been thoughtfully curated from the John F. Kennedy Presidential Library, Getty Images and private and family collections.



Of over 34,000 images found in these archives, the exhibit has selected 77 photographs to showcase. These photographs document Kennedy’s life from his first Congressional campaign to the aftermath of his assassination in 1963 and illustrate both his active political career and enigmatic personal life. The gallery is divided into rooms marking different periods of Kennedy’s career — “The Making of JFK,” “The Road to the White House” and the “The New Frontier” — each of which provide a new perspective on his presidency. The exhibit is based on the book “JFK: A Vision for America,” edited by Stephen Kennedy Smith and Douglas Brinkley, and has been organized by Lawrence Schiller, a photojournalist from Kennedy’s presidential campaign trail.

<em> The “American Visionary: John F Kennedy’s Life and Times” exhibit will be on display at the Smithsonian American Art Museum until Sept. 17. Read more online at thehoya.com.</em>

<strong>“Artist Soldiers: Artistic Expression in the First World War” </strong>



The National Air and Space Museum and the National Museum of American History have collaborated to produce “Artist Soldiers: Artistic Expression in the First World War,” an exhibit that re-examines World War I through the lens of art inspired by and created during the war. According to Peter Jakab, chief curator of the museum, the 1910s marked a time of significant cultural change, particularly with respect to attitude toward war. Artists began to move away from romanticized depictions of war toward a more authentic illustration of the tragic realities of battle.

Many of the pieces in “Artist Soldiers” have never before been seen by the public. Some are culled from the archives of the official U.S. war artists of the time: a group of professional artists commissioned to produce works that represented the experience of American soldiers in the war. Other works come from soldiers themselves, who provide raw and emotionally charged perspectives on their time in combat through painting, drawing, photography and other mediums of art.

<em> “Artist Soldiers: Artistic Expression in the First World War” is on display at the National Air and Space Museum until Nov. 11, 2018.</em>

<strong>“The Face of Battle: Americans at War, 9/11 to Now” </strong>

On April 7, the National Portrait Gallery opened “The Face of Battle: Americans at War, 9/11 to Now,” an exhibit committed to exploring and understanding the emotional and psychological effect of modern warfare on American soldiers. The gallery features 56 portraits by six contemporary photographers, in addition to a number of paintings, sculptures, drawings and other media-based artworks, including film and audio presentations.



Photographs in the exhibit shed light on the normalization of warfare in American society, particularly since the 9/11 attacks, and aim to humanize the experience of soldiers, both active and veteran. The gallery places a special focus on the theme of identity, looking at the threats to identity that soldiers may face while in battle. Although it explores the darker realities of war, the exhibit also hopes to celebrate soldiers’ commitment to their country and the honor the sacrifices they make in order to serve.

“The Face of Battle” continues the National Portrait Gallery’s “Portraiture Now” series, which promotes development in the realm of portrait-taking.

<em> “The Face of Battle: Americans at War, 9/11 to Now” is on view at the National Portrait Gallery until Jan. 28, 2018.</em>

<strong>“Markus Lüpertz: Threads of History”</strong>

Visitors to the Hirshhorn Museum and Sculpture Garden this summer will also be delighted to view the paintings of German contemporary artist Markus Lüpertz. Lüpertz is known for creating abstract, high-concept paintings and sculptures that incorporate religious and mythological symbolism and make reference to the history, culture and sociopolitical landscape of his birth country. His extensive body of work traces back to the 1960s, when he moved to Berlin from Paris, where he initially launched his career as an artist and began work on his first series of paintings. As his work progressed, Lüpertz began to emerge as a leading figure in the neo-expressionist movement of the 1970s, which rejected minimalist techniques in favor of more expressive, vivid art forms.



“Markus Lüpertz: Threads of History” will showcase the artist’s earlier paintings from the 1960s and 1970s with a focus on his pieces of abstract expressionism and pop art. Among these paintings will be his famous 40-foot work “Westwall [Siegfried Line],” in addition to more than 30 other pieces of art infrequently or never before displayed in the United States.

This gallery will be on view at the same time as the Phillips Collection’s upcoming exhibit, “Markus Lüpertz,” which displays select works from the artist’s entire career. This is Lüpertz’s first major showing in the United States, spanning two major museums. Visitors to the Hirshhorn and Phillips Collection can look forward to seeing the artist’s bold and colorful works, which not only broke artistic conventions of the time, but also sparked — and continue to encourage — intellectual discussion about the social and political landscape of Germany following World War II.

<em> “Markus Lüpertz: Threads of History” can be viewed at the Hirshhorn Museum and Sculpture Garden from May 24 to Sept. 10. Admission to the Hirshhorn is free. “Markus Lüpertz” will be on display at the Phillips Collection from May 27 to Sept. 3. For non-members, admission is $12 for adults and $10 for students and visitors 62 and over.</em><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com/museum-exhibits-across-the-district/">Museum Exhibits Across the District</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com"></a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thehoya.com/museum-exhibits-across-the-district/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Recent Album Releases</title>
		<link>http://www.thehoya.com/recent-album-releases/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thehoya.com/recent-album-releases/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 13:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Guide Editor]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Summer Highlights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Guide]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[albums]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[harry styles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Logic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[releases]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thehoya.com/?p=23074663</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Harry Styles ‘HARRY STYLES’ Formerly a member of British pop sensation One Direction, Harry Styles released his first solo studio album, “Harry Styles,” on May 12. Stepping away from his earlier boy band stardom has led Styles to makes his first real attempt at developing into a bona fide rock<a class="more-link" href="http://www.thehoya.com/recent-album-releases/">Read More</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com/recent-album-releases/">Recent Album Releases</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com"></a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<strong>Harry Styles</strong>

<strong>‘HARRY STYLES’</strong>



Formerly a member of British pop sensation One Direction, Harry Styles released his first solo studio album, “Harry Styles,” on May 12. Stepping away from his earlier boy band stardom has led Styles to makes his first real attempt at developing into a bona fide rock star. He uses his newfound freedom and space to create a comprehensive project showcasing his range of vocal talents through ballads and passionate rock anthems. With hit single “Sign of the Times” already topping the charts, Styles’ album is forecasted to debut at No. 1 on the Billboard 200. Fans are already loving the artist’s first showing, and critics have cited the ‘70s-influenced album as showing promise for the future. One thing is for sure —  Harry Styles, as his own solo entity, has arrived and is here to stay.

<strong>Zac Brown Band</strong>

<strong>‘WELCOME HOME’</strong>



Zac Brown Band, the maker of famous tunes like “Chicken Fried” and “Toes,” returns to its roots with the traditional country sounds that first brought the band to fame in 2008. “Welcome Home” is a great bounce back from “Jekyll + Hyde” in 2015, which received mixed reviews due to its non-cohesive sound. Although producing a more purely country sound on “Welcome Home” than it has in past albums, the band includes elements of pop and rock for its mainstream fan base. Zac Brown Band maintains the familiar feel of a laid-back summer afternoon in its latest music, providing comfort and relaxation to listeners and appealing to a wide variety of audiences.

<strong>LOGIC</strong>

<strong>‘EVERYBODY’</strong>



In his third studio album,  rapper Logic shows off his lyrical dexterity and rapid flows. Focused heavily on sociopolitical issues and preaching self-confidence, “Everybody” stays true to what Logic’s loyal fans have come to love and expect. He also approaches new fans with radio-ready hits like “1-800-273-8255,” which features popular singer-songwriters Alessia Cara and Khalid and maintains a positive message — in this case, encouraging others to choose life over suicide. Although receiving some negative reviews from hip-hop critics, the album’s success is immediately evident, gracing Logic with his first No. 1 slot on the Billboard 200. In a recent interview with online media base Genius, Logic said that his upcoming fourth album will likely be his last — a finale to his cohesive series of projects promoting uplifting messages in today’s hip-hop culture. With it, Logic hopes to cement a place as one of the great lyricists of his generation.

<strong>Gorillaz</strong>

<strong>‘HUMANZ’</strong>



After a six-year hiatus, British virtual band Gorillaz emerged with its fifth studio album, “Humanz,” an animated journey through its fictional universe, featuring rising artists like Vince Staples, Danny Brown and D.R.A.M. The band’s trademark gloomy sound fits perfectly with its theme of disconsolation, as the release is largely inspired by discontent surrounding Trump’s presidency, according to collaborator Pusha T in an appearance on Zane Lowe’s Beats 1 Radio. The mechanical sounds of synths and deep bass push listeners through an unfamiliar world where the artists’ animated selves reign. Although not full of happy summer anthems, “Humanz” is a compelling album with a variety of influential contributors, providing plenty of insightful commentary on modern political culture.<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com/recent-album-releases/">Recent Album Releases</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com"></a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thehoya.com/recent-album-releases/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Concerts and Festivals: Editor’s Picks</title>
		<link>http://www.thehoya.com/concerts-and-festivals-editors-picks/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thehoya.com/concerts-and-festivals-editors-picks/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 13:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Guide Editor]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Summer Highlights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Guide]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[9:30 Club]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[concerts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[festivals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[heritage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kendrick]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kendrick Lamar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mac]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mac demarco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[national mall]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smithsonian]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[verizon center]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thehoya.com/?p=23074648</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>May 23-24, 2016 - Mac DeMarco at the 9:30 Club Over the past 10 years, Canadian singer-songwriter Mac DeMarco has cultivated one of the most distinctive sounds of the indie genre, combining soft, echoing guitar arrangements with lazy, lo-fi vocals in what some have described as “slacker rock.” Earlier this<a class="more-link" href="http://www.thehoya.com/concerts-and-festivals-editors-picks/">Read More</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com/concerts-and-festivals-editors-picks/">Concerts and Festivals: Editor’s Picks</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com"></a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<em>May 23-24, 2016 - Mac DeMarco at the 9:30 Club</em>

Over the past 10 years, Canadian singer-songwriter Mac DeMarco has cultivated one of the most distinctive sounds of the indie genre, combining soft, echoing guitar arrangements with lazy, lo-fi vocals in what some have described as “slacker rock.” Earlier this month, DeMarco released his third full-length studio album, “This Old Dog,” a strong addition to his repertoire that both showcases the singer’s growing lyrical prowess and highlights his more introspective side.



DeMarco will take stage at the 9:30 Club twice this May, alongside supporting act Tonstartssbandht, an American psychedelic rock duo. DeMarco’s show promises to deliver a laid-back listening experience, as the singer plays fan-favorite hits like “Salad Days” and “Cooking Up Something Good,” as well as popular tracks from his latest album, such as “My Old Man.” For those unfamiliar with the indie rock scene, going to one of DeMarco’s concerts this summer — or any show at the 9:30 Club — may just be the perfect foray into the genre and D.C.’s vibrant alternative music scene.

Mac DeMarco plays at the 9:30 Club on May 23 and May 24. The concerts begin at 7 p.m. and tickets can be purchased for $35 through the venue’s official website.

<em>June 9-18, 2016 - DC Jazz Festival</em>

Although music lovers often associate the origin of jazz solely with the city of New Orleans, jazz music also has many of its roots in the nation’s capital. The District, in fact, is the birthplace of a number of legends of the genre, most prominently the iconic Duke Ellington, who fused a variety of musical styles to create a form of jazz still popular today. The D.C. Jazz Festival, originally named the Duke Ellington Jazz Festival, has been held each summer since 2005 to celebrate the historical and cultural significance of jazz and simply to provide fun summertime entertainment.



Visitors can attend over 125 performances by more than 300 soloists and 90 bands, up-and-coming and long-established musical acts alike. Over the two weeks, special events will be held at a number of landmark spots in D.C., including the Smithsonian Anacostia Museum, Howard Theatre and the John F. Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts. Other performances will be held at restaurants, clubs and hotels across the city, allowing jazz musicians to incorporate their art with other aspects of culture and day-to-day life in the District.

The D.C. Jazz Festival is scheduled from June 9 to 18. Events are scheduled at over 40 different locations and venues; a full itinerary is available at http://dcjazzfest.org/schedule.

<em>June 13, 2016 - July 16, 2016 - “The Sound of Music” at the Kennedy Center</em>



“The Sound of Music” has enjoyed enormous success since its Broadway debut in 1959 and has been reproduced a number of times since: most notably, in 1965, in the Academy Award-winning film adaptation starring Julie Andrews. The Kennedy Center’s production promises a fresh take on the time-honored story of Maria Rainer and the Von Trapp family, under the direction of three-time Tony Award-winner Jack O’Brien. O’Brien’s production, with a run time of 160 minutes — including a brief 20-minute intermission — will delight audiences of all ages as it delivers one of world’s most beloved musical scores. The production may just be one of D.C.’s “favorite things” this year!

“The Sound of Music” will run from June 13 to July 16 at the Opera House in the Kennedy Center. Tickets range from $39 to $149, and can be purchased online at the Kennedy Center’s website.

<em>June 14-18, 2016 - AFI Docs</em>



Every summer, the American Film Institute and the Discovery Channel join forces to host AFI Docs, an international documentary film festival held in Silver Spring, Md., and Washington, D.C. Now celebrating its 15th anniversary, the five-day event is dedicated to giving artists and filmmakers a platform to share their eye-opening stories with diverse audiences and to connect with others who share their beliefs. This year, AFI Docs will represent 28 countries by highlighting 103 films, a number of which will premiere at the festival. Among the most anticipated documentaries this year are “Inconvenient Sequel: Truth to Power,” which follows former Vice President Al Gore’s fight against climate change, and “Whitney: Can I Be Me,” which celebrates Whitney Houston’s legacy and explores the late singer’s personal struggles. AFI Docs hosts a number of special events in addition to these screenings, including the Impact Lab and AFI Docs Forum, both of which aim to promote the power of film to spark political and social movement.

AFI Docs runs from June 14 to 18 at several locations in Silver Spring, Md., and Washington, D.C. Tickets can be purchased at AFI.com/afidocs.

<em>Begins on June 29 - Smithsonian Folklife Festival</em>



The Smithsonian Folklife Festival has long served as a symbol of cultural exchange and awareness in the District. Celebrating its 50th anniversary this summer, the two-week celebration is held around the Fourth of July holiday, enhancing its message of national and cultural pride. Hosted by the Smithsonian Center for Folklife and Cultural Heritage, the festival is open to the public, drawing more than a million participants from across the country and globe, including artisans and tradition bearers from every state and nearly 90 countries, as well as a number of cultural groups, particularly from the Native American community. Throughout the day, visitors can enjoy musical and narrative performances, artistic exhibitions and foods from other cultures. This year, special programs will highlight youth and migration, as well as the rich history of circus arts in the United States. Smithsonian Folklife is one of the most engaging and enjoyable ways to learn more about other cultures. The best part? It all happens in the nation’s diverse capital, giving local residents the chance to have a taste of travel all in their own backyard — the National Mall.

The festival is free and runs from June 29 to July 4 and July 6 to 9. The schedule of events will be posted in early June on the festival’s official website.

<em> July 21 - Kendrick Lamar, Travis Scott and D.R.A.M. at the Verizon Center</em>



Kendrick Lamar has more than earned his title as one of the greatest artists in the hip-hop scene today. With seven Grammy Awards under his belt, he has established his legacy as a socially conscious rapper with a prolific and powerful message. Lamar’s fourth studio album, “DAMN.,” released in April, received universal critical acclaim, making fans more excited than ever to see the rapper perform. Lamar’s tour, produced by Live Nation, launches in Phoenix on July 12 and will stop at D.C.’s Verizon Center on July 21. The tour will feature special guest artists Travis Scott, who collaborated with Lamar on Scott’s track “Goosebumps” earlier this year, and D.R.A.M.

Doors will open at 6:30 p.m., and the concert will begin at 7:30 p.m. Tickets can be purchased through Kendrick Lamar’s official website; prices begin at $105.<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com/concerts-and-festivals-editors-picks/">Concerts and Festivals: Editor’s Picks</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com"></a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thehoya.com/concerts-and-festivals-editors-picks/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Breath of Fresh Air: Nature Near DC</title>
		<link>http://www.thehoya.com/a-breath-of-fresh-air-nature-near-dc/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thehoya.com/a-breath-of-fresh-air-nature-near-dc/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 13:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Guide Editor]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Summer Highlights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Guide]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ESCAPE]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[flowers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gardens]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[museum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outdoor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[park]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[plants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scenic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[woods]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thehoya.com/?p=23074678</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>The National Aroboretum Located in northeast Washington, D.C., the U.S. National Arboretum is a 446-acre living museum dedicated to enhancing the value of ornamental and landscape plants through research, conservation and exhibition. Featuring 9.5 miles of roadways, the Arboretum’s beautiful gardens can be explored by foot, bike or car. Although<a class="more-link" href="http://www.thehoya.com/a-breath-of-fresh-air-nature-near-dc/">Read More</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com/a-breath-of-fresh-air-nature-near-dc/">A Breath of Fresh Air: Nature Near DC</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com"></a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<em>The National Aroboretum</em>



Located in northeast Washington, D.C., the U.S. National Arboretum is a 446-acre living museum dedicated to enhancing the value of ornamental and landscape plants through research, conservation and exhibition. Featuring 9.5 miles of roadways, the Arboretum’s beautiful gardens can be explored by foot, bike or car. Although the Arboretum is free, for $30 visitors can take an after-hours hike  through the moonlit meadows, gardens and woods. Other special activities include the “Kid’s Climb,” the “Azalea Bonsai Exhibit: Putting on the Glitz” and “The Bonsai Saga: How 53 Japanese Bonsai Came to America.” Open from 8 a.m. to 4:30 p.m., the National Arboretum is the perfect destination for anyone looking to spend a summer day outdoors.

<em>U.S. Botanic Garden</em>



Created by Congress in 1820, the United States Botanic Garden is a perfect destination for history and plant lovers alike. As one of the oldest botanic gardens in North America, this living museum aims to demonstrate and promote the importance of celebrating and preserving the natural world, especially to the American youth population. Popular activities include taking a free guided tour of the grounds, photographing the beautiful landscape and spending the day sketching outdoors. The “You Can Grow It!” exhibit, on view until Oct. 17, allows visitors to learn more about gardening. Open 365 days a year, the Botanic Garden offers a peaceful respite from the busy city life at any time.

<em>Hillwood Estate, </em><em>Museum and Gardens</em>



The gorgeous Hillwood Estate, Museum and Gardens houses a comprehensive collection of Russian imperial art and French decorative antiquities. Guests can also view the original owner Marjorie Merriweather Post’s elaborate wardrobe and jewelry collection, as well as take an audio or guided tour of the mansion or gardens. Located just 5 miles from downtown Washington, the oasis of Hillwood can be reached by car or bike, with parking available on-site. Those who prefer to use the metro will have to take the red line and exit at the Van Ness-UDC station located 1 mile from the Estate. Admission is just $10 for college students, making the Hillwood Estate, Museum and Gardens an excellent and affordable place to escape for the day.

<em>Shenandoah Valley</em>



If you are looking to escape the hustle and bustle of D.C. for more than just a couple of hours, consider taking a weekend trip to Virginia’s breathtaking and historic Shenandoah National Park. The park contains over 500 miles of hiking trails through the Blue Ridge Mountains, including the most scenic stretch of the Appalachian Trail, making it a perfect destination for seasoned mountain-climbers and new adventurers alike.

Those who prefer a more mellow experience can enjoy a calming drive along Skyline Drive, the National Scenic Byway that rides along the crest of the Blue Ridge Mountains. Other popular valley activities include wine tasting, stargazing, horseback riding and outdoor concerts. After a long day of exploring the beauty of the park, guests can relax by booking a room at the Skyland, Blue Meadows Lodge, Lewis Mountains Cabins or by camping in the park itself. No matter your interests, a trip to Shenandoah National Park is sure to satisfy and provide a breath of fresh air.<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com/a-breath-of-fresh-air-nature-near-dc/">A Breath of Fresh Air: Nature Near DC</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com"></a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thehoya.com/a-breath-of-fresh-air-nature-near-dc/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
