<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>
		
	
<channel>
	
	<uid>EXAMPLE_CHANNEL_MULTI_ITEM_JSON_TTS_1</uid>
	<updateDate>2017-04-26T00:00:00.0Z</updateDate>
	<titleText>Multi Item JSON (TTS)</titleText>
	<mainText></mainText>
	<streamUrl>https://d366cdbbwqnolc.cloudfront.net/progressive/1602_QRPI0098000_Drivers_Seat_Mindfloness_15_NoSlate.mp3?slotId=6dc1b640-30f2-11a7-1692-0e9141af46f8
	</streamUrl>
	<redirectionUrl>http://voicelabs.co</redirectionUrl>
	
	<title></title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.thehoya.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://www.thehoya.com</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 May 2017 19:52:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=4.1.17</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Two-Thirds of University Email Accounts Targeted by Phishing Scam</title>
		<link>http://www.thehoya.com/university-email-accounts-targeted-by-phishing-scam/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thehoya.com/university-email-accounts-targeted-by-phishing-scam/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2017 21:32:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Campus News Editor]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News - Top]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[phishing scam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[university information services]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thehoya.com/?p=23074407</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>About 14,000 Georgetown email accounts were targeted within an hour by a widespread phishing scam involving fake Google Docs invitations Wednesday, leading some students and faculty to inadvertently compromise their accounts, according to Georgetown Chief Information Officer Judd Nicholson. Two-thirds of Georgetown email accounts were targeted by the nationwide scam, making it the<a class="more-link" href="http://www.thehoya.com/university-email-accounts-targeted-by-phishing-scam/">Read More</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com/university-email-accounts-targeted-by-phishing-scam/">Two-Thirds of University Email Accounts Targeted by Phishing Scam</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com"></a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[About 14,000 Georgetown email accounts were targeted within an hour by a widespread phishing scam involving fake Google Docs invitations Wednesday, leading some students and faculty to inadvertently compromise their accounts, according to Georgetown Chief Information Officer Judd Nicholson.

Two-thirds of Georgetown email accounts were targeted by the nationwide scam, making it the largest hacking campaign affecting the university in recent memory, according to Chief Information Security Officer Joseph Lee. Hackers successfully gained access to as many as 1 million total Gmail accounts, though a Google spokesperson said the hackers were only able to access contact information of victims, not their personal emails.

Though it is not unusual for the university to encounter smaller phishing attempts, Lee said Wednesday's campaign affected significantly more than past campaigns.

<strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">"We get them all the time, and it’s not just us, every university gets them," Lee said. "But t<strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">his one is fairly unique, in that it impacted about two-thirds of the university community."</span></strong></span></strong>

The scam involved emails inviting recipients to open a Google Doc, which, if opened, allowed hackers to gain access to recipients' Google accounts. The scam replicated itself by sending the same link to users' contacts. The emails, sent by hackers, were disguised to look as if they were sent from legitimate university email accounts — a practice known as "spoofing."

The scam emails were widely reported Wednesday afternoon, including at universities and major media organizations. Information technology experts said the scam was nearly impossible to detect, because it contained a real Google link and did not contain red flags, like spelling or formatting errors. In a statement posted to Twitter at 1:08 p.m., Google said it was investigating the scam and advised users not to open any unexpected Google invitations and to report any scam emails they receive.

To shut down the campaign, Google removed the fraudulent pages and applications and disabled the responsible Google accounts. The company resolved the scam within an hour, and updated its security features after the campaign to prevent similar scams in the future.

Lee said the university was working on steps to counter the hack and alerting affected Georgetown users when Google came out with their own fix.

"A<strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">s we were impacted, just like many other companies and universities were impacted, we were trying to figure out what steps to take and what instructions we needed to give to our university community," Lee said. "But as soon as we started doing that, Google took its own action."</span></strong>

The purpose of the scam remains unclear. Users initially feared the hackers would be capable of accessing the victims' emails or revoking the victim's access to their own account by changing the password, before Google's investigation discovered this was not the case, according to a Reddit threat discussing the scam shortly after it was discovered.

People affected by the scam were initially advised to revoke permissions for the false Google Docs program by accessing their account security settings. Google said Wednesday evening that no further action by users was necessary.

Nicholson said that in spite of occasional security breaches, the university email system has stronger security protections than most personal email accounts.

"<span style="font-weight: 400;">We have a multi-layered security approach for information within the university," Nicholson said. "We have spam control, we have firewalls that offer some level of protection. We also watch the borders, to ensure that if there is some malicious traffic coming in, that we can keep it out."</span>

<em>This post has been updated.</em><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com/university-email-accounts-targeted-by-phishing-scam/">Two-Thirds of University Email Accounts Targeted by Phishing Scam</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com"></a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thehoya.com/university-email-accounts-targeted-by-phishing-scam/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Theater Review: &#8216;Fun Home&#8217;</title>
		<link>http://www.thehoya.com/theater-review-fun-home/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thehoya.com/theater-review-fun-home/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 10:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Guide Editor]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Arts & Entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Guide]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arts and entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[comedy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[musical]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[national theatre]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the guide]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[theater]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[theater review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[visual and performing arts]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thehoya.com/?p=23074351</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Directed by Sam Gold and based on Alison Bechdel’s award-winning autobiographical graphic novel, Tony Award-winning musical “Fun Home” made its Washington, D.C. premiere April 18 at the National Theatre. The musical delivers a striking study of human relationships, particularly those between father and daughter, as its protagonist Alison, played by<a class="more-link" href="http://www.thehoya.com/theater-review-fun-home/">Read More</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com/theater-review-fun-home/">Theater Review: &#8216;Fun Home&#8217;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com"></a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[

Directed by Sam Gold and based on Alison Bechdel’s award-winning autobiographical graphic novel, Tony Award-winning musical “Fun Home” made its Washington, D.C. premiere April 18 at the National Theatre. The musical delivers a striking study of human relationships, particularly those between father and daughter, as its protagonist Alison, played by Kate Shindle, struggles to determine how alike she and her father are. They both grew up in the same small Pennsylvania town. They both love literature. And they are, as Alison eventually learns, both gay.

As she attempts to sort through her father’s story — and by extension, her own — Alison revisits memories of her childhood as Small Alison, played by Alessandra Baldacchino, and her freshman year at Oberlin College as Medium Alison, played by Abby Corrigan. Throughout this personal exploration, composer Jeanine Tesori’s music, replete with reprises that tie the present to the past, as well as the scenic design by David Zinn carry the audience down the winding memory lane. As Alison struggles to piece together her family’s history into a coherent narrative, she encounters her own blind spots and uncertainties.

The stunning set of “Fun Home” mirrors Alison’s personal journey throughout the play. Starting as a jumble of obscure, old-fashioned objects — Victorian-era furniture, an old silver teapot, a door with a sign marked “Gay Union” taped to it — punctuated by Alison’s present-day writing desk, the seemingly randomly designed set begins to take clearer form as she starts to unravel her own memories, with each recollection becoming more elaborate. In the final scene, as Alison walks into her family’s old living room in a final memory, the mismatch of couches and piano have become a full-fledged, elaborately decorated interior: Alison’s past as she lived it, in vivid detail.

Alison’s rediscovery of her past as she attempts to understand her family’s story is intertwined with her own journey of self-discovery and early conflicts over her own identity: arguments with her father about wearing dresses as a young child, identifying with a butch delivery woman in a luncheonette and her first sexual encounter at college.

Despite its utter sincerity, “Fun Home" remains keenly aware of the irony of its own story — the title refers to a funeral home, called the “Fun Home” by young children who grow up with death as a fact of life. There is a continuous emphasis on the intersection of the mundane and the grave — Alison’s father catches his children hiding in a casket as they cheerfully rehearse a commercial for the family business, for example — which drifts from hilarious to haunting as tragedy becomes personal. All the while, Alison attempts to mine meaning from the smallest details of her childhood recollections in her hunt for answers.

It is easy to see why “Fun Home” won five of the 12 Tony Awards for which it was nominated, including Best Musical: Its music is stunning and well-placed. More impressively, the impulse for Broadway theatrics never overwhelms the show’s true strength — its story and the realness of its characters. Shindle is captivating as the smart and funny but haunted Alison, while the three younger cast members — Baldacchino as Small Alison, and Pierson Salvador and Lennon Nate Hammond as her brothers Christian and John — never fail to delight.

Perhaps the most powerful performance is delivered by Robert Petkoff, who portrays Alison’s father, Bruce, a character who easily wins over the audience even as Alison herself struggles with her feelings toward him. Bruce and Alison’s duets, which at times take place with Bruce in the past and Alison in the present, are the strongest parts of a show that has few noticeable weaknesses, illustrating the immense vocal and acting talents of the cast.

Performed without an intermission, “Fun Home” allows the audience to reflect on the undecided fate of the protagonist: Alison is ultimately left to draw her own conclusions about her family and herself.

Early in the show, Small Alison and Bruce fight about a school assignment, as he attempts to teach her to draw a realistic landscape and she resists with a cartoon depiction. “Maps show you what is simple and true,” Alison sings, but their conflict gives a more realistic picture: What you see depends on who you are, and Bruce’s story may never be truly understood by Alison, no matter how alike — or different — she and her father are.

“FUN HOME” runs at the National Theatre through May 13. Tickets are priced $48 — $98 and are available at thenationaldc.org.<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com/theater-review-fun-home/">Theater Review: &#8216;Fun Home&#8217;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com"></a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thehoya.com/theater-review-fun-home/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>VIEWPOINT: The Dilemma of the Underpaid Adjunct</title>
		<link>http://www.thehoya.com/viewpoint-dilemma-underpaid-adjunct/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thehoya.com/viewpoint-dilemma-underpaid-adjunct/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 01:15:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Opinion Editor]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion - Top]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adjunct]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[equal pay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tenure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[viewpoint]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women's and gender studies]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thehoya.com/?p=23074387</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>With love and regret, I am saying farewell to Georgetown after 21 wonderful years on the faculty of the women’s and gender studies program and a recent, shiny Silver Vicennial Medal for my two decades of service. I will miss you all and, in particular, my beloved Hoya athletes, so<a class="more-link" href="http://www.thehoya.com/viewpoint-dilemma-underpaid-adjunct/">Read More</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com/viewpoint-dilemma-underpaid-adjunct/">VIEWPOINT: The Dilemma of the Underpaid Adjunct</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com"></a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[With love and regret, I am saying farewell to Georgetown after 21 wonderful years on the faculty of the women’s and gender studies program and a recent, shiny Silver Vicennial Medal for my two decades of service. I will miss you all and, in particular, my beloved Hoya athletes, so many of whom took my popular “Athletics and Gender” class or my “Intro to Women’s Studies” class. Yet, the women’s and gender studies program remains in the good hands of its devoted chair, You-Me Park, to whom I owe so many teaching years here at Georgetown — years rich in culture, community, the love and respect of co-workers and the pleasure of campus life.

So, at the top of my game, with 15 books published and a recent exhibit at the Library of Congress, why leave the Hilltop? The answer is painful: <a href="http://www.thehoya.com/editorial-value-faculty-protect-union/">Like many non-tenured faculty</a>, I can no longer afford to live in Washington, D.C. Since 1996, I have cheerfully combined two half-time appointments, at both Georgetown and The George Washington University. Neither school offers tenure or promotion for faculty in women’s studies, which at both institutions is an underfunded program<em>, </em>rather than a department<em>. </em>For almost a decade now, to make ends meet, I have taught a load of eight courses per year, paid either per course or half of what I would earn in a tenure-track position. Now, thanks to budget cuts, I have no benefits at either institution and pay out of pocket for medical expenses at age 55.

Stories like mine are common among adjunct professors: We love what we do, you love us and we energetically work at two or three jobs until we wear ourselves out. The moral dilemma is that in the underfunded area of women’s studies, I teach<em> </em>the history of equal pay for equal work, while not receiving it myself. By continuing to accept a pay rate that is not on par with those who teach less and publish less, I can no longer call myself a good feminist role model to the young women who constitute the majority of Georgetown undergraduates. As an underpaid adjunct in an underfunded program, I can no longer sit idly by.

I have sought solutions and sent proposals, but we simply are not seeing the financial dedication to the women’s history field that I assumed would be the case by 2017. Now, with my mother growing older, I have an invitation to come live and write at my family home in California, where I can continue to be a consultant archivist to the Smithsonian Institution and the Library of Congress while lecturing part time in the University of California system. My 79-year-old mother, my 21-year-old niece and I will be three generations, in one house, committed to the production of art and activism around women’s lives. With my all-too-common story in mind, I invite you to consider the need for change in our institutions, so that a living wage is within the reach of all teaching faculty who gave up safer career choices to inspire future generations.

<strong><em>Bonnie J. Morris</em></strong><em> is an adjunct assistant professor in the women’</em><em>s and gender studies program.</em><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com/viewpoint-dilemma-underpaid-adjunct/">VIEWPOINT: The Dilemma of the Underpaid Adjunct</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com"></a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thehoya.com/viewpoint-dilemma-underpaid-adjunct/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Suspects Identified in Healy Tower Clock Hands Theft</title>
		<link>http://www.thehoya.com/healy-tower-clock-hands-stolen/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thehoya.com/healy-tower-clock-hands-stolen/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 16:29:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Campus News Editor]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Campus News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News - Top]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[clock hands]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[healy tower]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tradition]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thehoya.com/?p=23074365</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>At least two students have been referred to the Office of Student Conduct after the clock hands were stolen from the clock tower of Healy Hall early Monday morning and replaced with an inflatable unicorn head, according to the Georgetown University Police Department. GUPD Chief Jay Gruber did not immediately confirm how<a class="more-link" href="http://www.thehoya.com/healy-tower-clock-hands-stolen/">Read More</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com/healy-tower-clock-hands-stolen/">Suspects Identified in Healy Tower Clock Hands Theft</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com"></a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[

<span style="font-weight: 400;">At least two students have been referred to the Office of Student Conduct after the clock hands were stolen from the clock tower of Healy Hall early Monday morning and replaced with an inflatable unicorn head, according to the Georgetown University Police Department.</span>

GUPD Chief Jay Gruber did not immediately confirm how the suspects were apprehended,  but said the department uses all tools at its disposal, including fingerprinting evidence, when identifying suspects in crime investigations. According to a conversation between GUPD officers, the department examined the inflatable unicorn head for fingerprints.

<span style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The theft, first reported by students on social media Monday morning, marks the last day of the spring 2017 semester, as well as the latest iteration in a long-standing Georgetown tradition last honored December 2014. According to lore, the </span><a href="http://www.thehoya.com/healy-clock-theft-has-roots-in-gu-history/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">history of the heist</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> goes back decades at least. The clock hands were stolen so frequently in the 1960s, it is said, the university stopped replacing them.</span></span>

The clock hands were returned to the tower by Monday afternoon, as the missing pair was initially replaced with a spare set, according to a GUPD officer. GUPD announced Tuesday afternoon it had recovered the stolen clock hands and identified suspects in the theft.

"The GUPD investigation has resulted in the return of the clock hands and the identification of the students responsible, who will be referred to the Office of Student Conduct," Gruber wrote in an email to The Hoya. "This is a serious matter that puts those involved in danger and destroys university property. I would like to thank the GUPD officers involved in the investigation and the other University officials who helped bring this matter to a close."

The administration has responded to the tradition at different times with consternation, acceptance or tacit veneration. After the last incident in 2014, the university <a href="http://www.thehoya.com/tradition-returns-with-theft-of-healy-clock-hands/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">responded to the theft</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> by posting a photo of the clock tower with the hashtag #TimelessTradition on social media.</span>

<span style="font-weight: 400;">However, the administration has taken a harder line in the past, once sentencing a pair of students to </span><a href="http://www.thehoya.com/healy-duo-receives-one-year-probation/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">community service and a year of disciplinary probation</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> after they accepted blame for removing the hands.</span>

<strong><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">This is a developing story. This post will be updated as more information becomes available.</span></i></strong><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com/healy-tower-clock-hands-stolen/">Suspects Identified in Healy Tower Clock Hands Theft</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com"></a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thehoya.com/healy-tower-clock-hands-stolen/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Album Review: &#8216;DAMN.&#8217;</title>
		<link>http://www.thehoya.com/album-review-damn/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thehoya.com/album-review-damn/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2017 22:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Guide Editor]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Guide]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[album]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beats]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[compton]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DAMN]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DNA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hip hop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HUMBLE]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kendrick]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kendrick Lamar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rapper]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rihanna]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thehoya.com/?p=23074358</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>★★★★★ At the end of “Ab-Soul’s Outro,” the penultimate track on Kendrick Lamar’s 2011 debut album “Section.80,” the Compton, Calif. rapper emphatically declared, “I’m not the next pop star / I’m not the next socially aware rapper.” Over the next four years, however, this proclamation would prove quite false: the<a class="more-link" href="http://www.thehoya.com/album-review-damn/">Read More</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com/album-review-damn/">Album Review: &#8216;DAMN.&#8217;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com"></a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[

★★★★★

At the end of “Ab-Soul’s Outro,” the penultimate track on Kendrick Lamar’s 2011 debut album “Section.80,” the Compton, Calif. rapper emphatically declared, “I’m not the next pop star / I’m not the next socially aware rapper.” Over the next four years, however, this proclamation would prove quite false: the spectacular “Good Kid, M.A.A.D City” catapulted the then-25-year-old artist to international fame in 2012, and “To Pimp a Butterfly” was a jaw-dropping meditation on what it means to be black in a troubled America in 2015.

On “DAMN.,” Lamar continues to expand on the narrative thread that has run through all four of his albums, trying to determine how to manage his spirituality, fear and insecurities in light of hip-hop superstardom. It is a life of contradictions, and “DAMN.” vividly reflects the battles raging inside his soul: between pride and humility, love and lust, wicked and weakness and more.

In many ways, this is his darkest and most self-isolated album to date. “Ain’t nobody prayin’ for me” is a phrase that appears throughout the album, and Lamar — never one to shy away from expressing his vulnerabilities — does not hold back. “I feel like I’m losin’ my patience / I feel like my thoughts in the basement,” he raps on “FEEL.” At times, it seems as though Lamar feels his self-sacrifice and fight for social justice have all been for nothing; on “PRIDE.,” he laments that “Promises are broken and more resentment come alive /Race barriers make inferior of you and I.”

Sonically, “DAMN.” is a radical departure from anything Lamar has taken on before. Rather than delve further into the jazz-fusion genre, or move into an entirely new realm of experimental production, the album largely fits within a more commercial, mainstream soundscape — a fact that certainly helped it quickly become Lamar’s fastest selling album, retailing a staggering 603,000 total units in its first week and giving him his third No. 1 on the Billboard charts.

Lamar enlists surefire hit-maker DJ Dahi and pop empress Rihanna on the infinitely catchy “LOYALTY.” “LOVE.,” featuring an ethereal hook from singer Zacari reminiscent of rhythm and blues singer The Weeknd, is his most heartfelt, radio-friendly ballad to date. Album standout “HUMBLE.” is sitting at No. 1 on the Hot 100, and with good reason: over a bouncy, Mike WiLL Made-It produced instrumental, Lamar gleefully asserts his dominance over the rap world while imploring his rivals to “sit down; be humble.”

As good as “HUMBLE.” may be, though, it is not Lamar’s best collaboration on the project. Rather, that title belongs to standout track “DNA.” Over a bombastic, distorted, Rick James-sampling beat — “Gimme some ganja!” — Lamar unleashes his most aggressive, take-no-prisoners flow since “Backseat Freestyle” from “Good Kid, M.A.A.D City.”  Alternating between extravagant boasts — “sleepin’ in a villa, sippin’ from a Grammy” — and searing self-criticism — “I got dark, I got evil, that rot inside my DNA” — it is by far the album’s most explosive track.

Besides Rihanna and Zacari, the only other feature on “DAMN.” is U2, an unexpected guest artist. Given Lamar’s complex, multifaceted approach to music, it is no surprise that he would want to collaborate with one of the biggest rock bands in history. Still, as always, he flips the script. “XXX.” is essentially two songs in one. The first half, a relentless, vengeful attack on the killer of a friend’s only son, gives way to a scathing indictment of the violent culture that often exists in the United States. “It's murder on my street, your street, back streets, Wall Street,” Lamar raps. “Is America honest, or do we bask in sin?”

The emotional apex of the album is undoubtedly “FEAR.” The concept of fear — of failure, judgment, loneliness and damnation — is at the heart of the album. Over subdued, blues-sampling production courtesy of The Alchemist, Lamar walks the listener through his two-decadelong journey of anxiety and fear: as a seven-year-old scared of misbehaving and catching a beating from his mother; a 17-year-old worried he would be killed simply walking the streets of Compton; and a 27-year-old increasingly paranoid about his legacy and the pitfalls of fame and fortune. “My biggest fear was being judged,” he reveals. “How they look at me reflect on myself, my family, my city.”

Lamar is and always has been a masterful storyteller, and that skill is on full display in the album’s closer, “DUCKWORTH.” The track serves as a kind of origin story. Anthony from Compton spares Ducky from Chicago’s life during a Kentucky Fried Chicken robbery. Years later, Ducky’s son, revealed to be Kendrick himself, signs to Anthony’s record label, Top Dawg Entertainment, which Lamar belongs to today. It is an incredible tale, and Lamar delivers it with the utmost precision and detail.

After four amazing albums, it is increasingly difficult to regard Lamar as anything other than one of the greatest rappers of all time. His technical skill, artistic vision and constant reinvention, flawlessly executed, set him far apart from his peers. “DAMN.” may not be his most earth-shattering record — that title remains with “To Pimp a Butterfly” — but it is his most impressive. Balancing profound introspection with genuine pop appeal, it is simply a masterpiece.<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com/album-review-damn/">Album Review: &#8216;DAMN.&#8217;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com"></a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thehoya.com/album-review-damn/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>HIGH-FUNCTIONING FAILURE: How to Make Male Friends</title>
		<link>http://www.thehoya.com/high-functioning-failure-how-to-make-male-friends/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thehoya.com/high-functioning-failure-how-to-make-male-friends/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 19:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Guide Editor]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Guide Columns]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Guide]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[companions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[failure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[friends]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[funny]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HFF]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[male]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[male friendship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[satire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tips]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thehoya.com/?p=23074294</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Ah, male friendship — just like dating, but with less handholding and sometimes more cuddling, depending on the companion. These friendships are especially formative for men as they prepare to go out in the world. When I think back to my days of youth, I cannot help but be struck<a class="more-link" href="http://www.thehoya.com/high-functioning-failure-how-to-make-male-friends/">Read More</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com/high-functioning-failure-how-to-make-male-friends/">HIGH-FUNCTIONING FAILURE: How to Make Male Friends</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com"></a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[Ah, male friendship — just like dating, but with less handholding and sometimes more cuddling, depending on the companion. These friendships are especially formative for men as they prepare to go out in the world. When I think back to my days of youth, I cannot help but be struck with memories of afternoons spent biking around the lake with my friend Brian, mornings spent making pancakes with my pal Cole and evenings spent journaling about how good those memories would be as fodder for the introductory paragraph of a collegiate newspaper column. Ah, the glory days.

Male companionship can be hard, however, as captured by the lauded 1980 sitcom “Bosom Buddies,” in which Tom Hanks and Peter Scolari play two men who dress in drag in order to maintain their apartment in a women-only hotel. Actually, wait — I really just wanted to point out that this was actually a television program. CBS actually made two-time Oscar-winner Tom Hanks act in a sitcom in which the entire premise was, “wouldn’t it be silly if these men dressed up like ladies?” Guess what they named their fake women-only hotel? “The Susan B Anthony Hotel.” Really subtle, CBS Studios.  Take your Billy-Joel-written theme song — again, not a joke — and get out. Anyway, back to this example. Men’s relationships are strong, and sometimes we dress like ladies. I believe that is where I was going.

Regardless, perhaps you are looking to acquire a male friendship for yourself. Maybe you are looking for someone to give a sweet high-five to after finishing a fresh, cool Budweiser, as this is something that I am told men do. Then, let me help you discover the elusive ballet that is male friendship. Here are a few tips and pointers:

Tip 1: Men Love Sports

Sports! Men just cannot get enough. Whether it is foot-sport, basket-sport or base-sport, sports are something men love to talk about. I was at a splendid Lady Gaga concert this past fall, and did not understand why so many of my male friends had joined me for the performance. As it turns out, I was at “Superbowl LI,” one of the largest sporting events of the year. Lady Gaga was actually some sort of an intermission performer, rather than top bill. Needless to say, I was shocked. It did not even have the patriotic falconry show that was promised to follow.

Tip 2: Did Someone Say Emotions?

No. No one did. That is because men do not like emotions. Based on the research I have conducted, men do not accept emotions as currency. I have cried in front of many men, from football coaches to middle school gym teachers to mini-golf instructors. They were not swayed by my tears. I still had to run the mile, climb the rope and putt through the windmill.  Men are emotionless hell demons; tailor your relationships accordingly.

Tip 3: Loud Noises

It is very simple — men love loud noises. From the sound of race cars to the blasting of fighter jets, loud noises are male friendship gold. Make sure your male relationships are dominated by loud sounds. Sometimes this means the occasional “whoop” in mid-conversation or a subtle “yeehaw” upon hearing satisfactory news. For example:

“Huh, apparently the gas tank is on the left.”

“Yeehaw!”

“Thanks, Jerry.”

Now that is male emotional support. And if you run into an uncomfortable silence with your male friend-partner, consider blasting Keith Urban’s “Long Hot Summer” through the nearest stereo. All men love this.

Now there you go, chief! Watch the male friendships roll on in like the tide!

This is also my final column with The Hoya, so if you have any questions, I am available at [EMAIL WITHHELD] or [PHONE NUMBER WITHHELD]. And if they block out my number, then you can go tell them to [VAGUELY-WORDED THREAT WITHHELD].

<img class="alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-23070365" src="http://www.thehoya.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/B3_columnist_AlexMitchell-150x150.png" alt="B3_columnist_AlexMitchell" width="150" height="150" />Alex Mitchell is a junior in the College. <strong>HIGH-FUNCTIONING FAILURE</strong> appears every other Friday.<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com/high-functioning-failure-how-to-make-male-friends/">HIGH-FUNCTIONING FAILURE: How to Make Male Friends</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com"></a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thehoya.com/high-functioning-failure-how-to-make-male-friends/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>ON TAP: The Drink Guide</title>
		<link>http://www.thehoya.com/on-tap-the-drink-guide/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thehoya.com/on-tap-the-drink-guide/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 17:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Guide Editor]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Food & Drink]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Guide Columns]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Guide]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adams morgan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chocolate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cider]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coffee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drinks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hot chocolate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[juice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[juicery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kombucha]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[on tap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[savory]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sweet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tea]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thehoya.com/?p=23074292</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Washington, D.C., is often portrayed as a city driven by its political agenda and business networks, leaving to the side recognition of the innovative creativity in its music, food and art. However, throughout our explorations within the city, we have seen that foodies have affirmed their craft within Washington, particularly<a class="more-link" href="http://www.thehoya.com/on-tap-the-drink-guide/">Read More</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com/on-tap-the-drink-guide/">ON TAP: The Drink Guide</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com"></a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[Washington, D.C., is often portrayed as a city driven by its political agenda and business networks, leaving to the side recognition of the innovative creativity in its music, food and art.

However, throughout our explorations within the city, we have seen that foodies have affirmed their craft within Washington, particularly in places like Shaw, Adams Morgan and NoMa. Hidden in these cherished locations is a food culture that the District has never seen before.

In our previous On Tap articles, we have delved into some of these emerging areas and discovered companies that provide high quality and niche drinks. As we finally end this column, we want to leave you with a guide to some of the best drinks in Washington. We hope that you will break the Georgetown bubble, explore beyond conventional hangout spots and experience a taste of something new.

<strong>For the Caffeine Buzz: Coffee and Tea</strong>

<em> </em>Swing’s Coffee:

Established in D.C. in 1916, this coffee roaster is no doubt a D.C. institution. The coffee bar’s newest location opened this February in Metropolitan Square, just steps away from the White House. This coffee bar offers three custom taps serving cold brew, nitro cold brews and lattes. Try the nitro lattes; they are made with a coffee brew pumped with nitrogen gas, for a deliciously smooth drink.

Located on 640 14th St. NW, Washington, D.C. 20005

Teaism:

Serving 20 different types of tea, hot and cold, there is a drink here for anyone. Teaism has a rustic homey feel, with every order served in personal tea pots. Also, make sure to order a bento box with your tea. The combination of Teaism’s food with its tea makes the experience even more enjoyable.

Locations in Dupont, Penn Quarter and Lafayette Park

<strong>For the Body and Mind: Kombucha and Juice</strong>

Capital Kombucha:

Founded by three business school graduates of George Washington University, Capital Kombucha has a simple and laid-back ambience. It is one of the first D.C.-based kombucha companies and provides its craft not only within the District, but also in locations as far out as New York City.

You can buy Capital Kombucha throughout the city in grocery stores like Whole Foods and Mom’s Organic Market.

JRINK Juicery:

JRINK uses cold-press method to juice its produce. This means the juicery crushes and presses its produce to obtain the juice, instead of using a fast-spinning blade and centrifuge to separate pulp. Overall cold press does not conduct heat, allowing the juice and its nutrients to be more fresh and long-lasting. Using only fruit and vegetable produce in its juice, JRINK makes its taste smooth, simple and fresh.

Locations in Foggy Bottom, Adams Morgan and Dupont Circle.

<strong>For the Sweet Tooth: Hot Chocolate and Cider</strong>

The Chocolate House:

Serving as D.C.’s one-stop chocolate shop, this little chocolate boutique is packed with the best chocolates from all over the world and offers classes on chocolate tasting and making.

The Chocolate House’s drink menu solely offers hot chocolate, and it is one of the best hot chocolates you will find in D.C. Using the highest-quality milk and chocolate, the distinguishing feature of this treat is in fact the Mexican chocolate that is used. With a hint of spiciness in the chocolate, this body-warming hot drink is perfect for the colder months.

Located on 1904 18th St. NW, Washington, D.C. 20009

FARMFRESH:

Every Sunday morning, you can find all sorts of certified organic ingredients and produce at this Dupont Circle farmers market. Sample and stroll through over 50 stalls offering a plethora of locally sourced fruits and vegetables, artisanal baked goods and cheeses and more.

Be sure to sample the varieties of apples, as well as the freshest cider you can find at Toigo Orchards. Pick up a pint of FARMFRESH’s honeycrisp apple cider for a sweet and refreshing treat after spending the morning strolling through the market.

Located next to the Dupont Circle Station on Sundays, 8:30 a.m. to 1:30 p.m.

<img class="alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-23070378" src="http://www.thehoya.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/B5_OnTap_Columnist-150x150.png" alt="B5_OnTap_Columnist" width="150" height="150" />Anna Jorgensen and Jackie Liang are sophomores in the College. This is the first installment of <strong>ON TAP</strong>.<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com/on-tap-the-drink-guide/">ON TAP: The Drink Guide</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com"></a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thehoya.com/on-tap-the-drink-guide/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Album Review: &#8216;Being No One, Going Nowhere&#8217;</title>
		<link>http://www.thehoya.com/album-review-being-no-one-going-nowhere/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thehoya.com/album-review-being-no-one-going-nowhere/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 15:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Guide Editor]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Guide]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[album]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[band]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[indie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rock]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[STRFKR]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thehoya.com/?p=23074290</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>For indie rock buffs across the country, this is an exciting decade. Since the genre broke into the mainstream in the early 2000s, the style and tone of the music has radically matured, departing from its grunge and classic rock roots to becoming an entirely new genre. STRFKR’s new album<a class="more-link" href="http://www.thehoya.com/album-review-being-no-one-going-nowhere/">Read More</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com/album-review-being-no-one-going-nowhere/">Album Review: &#8216;Being No One, Going Nowhere&#8217;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com"></a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[

For indie rock buffs across the country, this is an exciting decade. Since the genre broke into the mainstream in the early 2000s, the style and tone of the music has radically matured, departing from its grunge and classic rock roots to becoming an entirely new genre. STRFKR’s new album “Being No One, Going Nowhere” exhibits the changes contemporary indie rock has experienced, blending rock and electronic elements into a genre that is both excitingly novel and enjoyable.

In many ways, STRFKR is a strange band. Since its founding in 2007, the Portland-based band has managed to produce poppy, energetic indie beats, while studiously avoiding the tropes and cliches that have beset both the pop and indie genres. This careful balance is revealed in the band’s name, which began as an ironic wink on the part of Joshua Hodges, STRFKR’s founder.

Avoiding easy categorization, “Being No One, Going Nowhere” is an amalgamation of several trends in indie music, combining pop-rock rhythms and electronic innovations to form a new sound. STRFKR represents the culmination of two decades of groundbreaking indie music in the United States, revealing the influence of electronic musicians on the indie scene through the liberal use of synthesizers and electronic beats. Experimental electronic sounds are not used simply for the sake of quirkiness but are crafted with traditional instrumentation to great effect. Arguably the best song on the album, “Open Your Eyes,” features a combination of guitar and electronic sounds, accompanied by hypnotic lyrics melded together to create a sound that feels fresh and focused.

Despite its complex influences and inspirations, STRFKR’s music remains fun, bubbly and fast-paced. Danceable beats mingle with enigmatic lyrics and electric guitar to make songs that call both for deeper listening and sheer joy of movement. “Being No One, Going Nowhere” proves that good music can also be fun music. This last quality cannot be overstated. As Hodges once said in 2014, the band’s goal is to make “dance music that you can actually listen to, that's good pop songs, but also you can dance to it." Despite its similarities to upbeat dance music, STRFKR’s music touches on deeper subjects through thoughtful lyrics, exploring issues such as the nature of being, death and the purpose of life. Lectures of the philosopher Alan Watts are frequently sampled and garbled, adding a mysterious quality to many of their lyrics.

“Being No One, Going Nowhere” offers a vision of what indie rock could be. By borrowing from varied genres and techniques with a keen eye on both the pleasure and the art of their music, STRFKR has made an album that points to the future of good indie music. STRFKR and other indie rock bands are riding the bleeding edge of new music, demonstrating the potent possibilities of artists who are not afraid to break from established genres and transform them in the process.<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com/album-review-being-no-one-going-nowhere/">Album Review: &#8216;Being No One, Going Nowhere&#8217;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com"></a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thehoya.com/album-review-being-no-one-going-nowhere/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Interview with Georgetown Band Almeda</title>
		<link>http://www.thehoya.com/interview-with-georgetown-band-almeda/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thehoya.com/interview-with-georgetown-band-almeda/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 13:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Guide Editor]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Features]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Guide]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[almeda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[band]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Georgetown]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[interview]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Performance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[r&b]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[recording]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rock]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[student]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[studio]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thehoya.com/?p=23074288</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>The Washington, D.C. music scene is among the nation’s best, boasting stadium-sized concert halls and offbeat venues all within a few streets of each other. Georgetown students, however, need look no further than their own campus to find exciting new sources of music and performance. Bands formed by students often<a class="more-link" href="http://www.thehoya.com/interview-with-georgetown-band-almeda/">Read More</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com/interview-with-georgetown-band-almeda/">Interview with Georgetown Band Almeda</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com"></a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[

The Washington, D.C. music scene is among the nation’s best, boasting stadium-sized concert halls and offbeat venues all within a few streets of each other. Georgetown students, however, need look no further than their own campus to find exciting new sources of music and performance. Bands formed by students often perform at venues on or close to campus, sparking a culture of artistic creativity all within the bounds of Healy Gates.

Almeda is a rhythm-and-blues and rock group formed by Georgetown students, featuring Dan Sheehan (COL ’17) on drums, Nick Quirk (COL ’17) on bass, Danny O’Brien (MSB ’17) on piano and guitar and Adaeze “Dez” Eze (SFS ’17) on vocals.  The band has performed in a variety of settings, from house shows in Georgetown to restaurants in Adams Morgan.  Almeda was voted the winner of the Adams Morgan PorchFest music festival in October.

Through SoundCloud and Bandcamp, Almeda has released an eponymous, three-song extended play and a single, “Wanderer.”  The group plans to release another extended play titled “Piece of Mind,” in collaboration with rapper Kenyon Smutherman (SFS '17).  The lead single, also called “Piece of Mind,” will be released in the next two weeks.

The Hoya sat down with Sheehan, Quirk and O’Brien for an exclusive interview to discuss the band’s influences, recent releases and future plans. Their responses have been edited for brevity and clarity.

<strong>How did Almeda form?</strong>

<strong>O'Brien:</strong> Me and Nick have been roommates all through college starting freshman year, and Dez was also on our floor.  She used to sing and everyone knew that she had a great voice.  Sophomore year, we finally convinced Dez to be in a band with us.  And then Nick knew Dan from one of his freshman seminars and knew that he was a drummer.

<strong>Quirk:</strong> We did “Guild of Bands,” a performance organization and course at Georgetown, sophomore year and junior year.  “Guild of Bands” is really good because you get rehearsal space and instrument amps, so we did that for logistics and it worked out really well.  And then from there, we just moved on.

<strong>Can you talk about your process in creating a song or making music in general?</strong>

<strong>O'Brien:</strong> All of us take turns being the lead song writer on different songs, so it really depends on who's leading it.  For one of our new songs, Dez just came in and was like, “Guys, I have a song,” and she started singing this baseline. We just jammed. We figured our way around it.  Whereas other times, me or Dan might come to the band with more of a developed chord progression or melody and then we work on it from there.  But it's almost always sort of spontaneous, working as a band to feel out our parts in real time as we play new songs.  And then we sit on a song for a long time, play it over and over again, develop the little things and tweak it so that by the time it's recorded, it's got all sorts of overdubbed layers and it becomes a bigger and bigger thing the longer we go.

<strong>Quirk:</strong> I'd definitely say a lot of the cool stuff comes in the recordings compared to what we play live because live we're only four people, but when you do recording, you can put background vocals and auxiliary percussion or horns on it.

<strong>How do you adapt to playing songs live after you have used those techniques in the studio?</strong>

<strong>Sheehan:</strong> It is challenging.  One of the songs I wrote, when we play it live, I usually play keys and then Danny drums … That's not what's on the recording, but it's what works best for the live performance.  It's just a matter of playing around with stuff.

<strong>O'Brien:</strong> It's usually a matter of simplifying the arrangement a little bit and trying to make up for it in energy.

<strong>Where have you performed so far and what are your upcoming shows?</strong>

<strong>Sheehan:</strong> We've performed a few shows in Adams Morgan.  We played at Bossa last year and we just played there again last week.  We've also played at Roofers Union there.  Back in the fall, we won Adams Morgan PorchFest, which is a festival where they have all these different bands play on porches around the neighborhood.

<strong>O'Brien:</strong> For PorchFest, we're playing another show May 6.  That's probably our biggest upcoming gig, in Adams Morgan.   There's a good culture of music kids hosting things at their houses.  It's pretty connected.  A lot of that is from “Guild of Bands.” People know each other, and so those have been some of the most fun shows, going to different houses and doing smaller gigs.

<strong>Do you have advice to other students who are looking to start a band?</strong>

<strong>O'Brien:</strong> Join “Guild of Bands.”  If you're looking for where to start or where to get the gear you need, look up “Guild of Bands” because that's really the main way that Georgetown facilitates this sort of thing, and you'll find the right people to talk to that way.

<strong>Quirk:</strong> Typically start playing some cover songs and then figure out your inspirations.  First thing you’ve got to do when you start a band is figure out your inspirations.

<strong>Sheehan:</strong> That is a big part of it, though.  Figure out what everyone listens to, and start listening to the same things and share your interests.

<strong>Who are some of your musical influences and artists you admire?</strong>

<strong>O'Brien:</strong> Lianne La Havas, Hiatus Kaiyote, Kendrick [Lamar], Allen Stone, Stevie Wonder.

<strong>What are Almeda's plans for the future?</strong>

<strong>O’Brien:</strong> We're basically on a recording spree right now.  We're recording as much material as we possibly can so that once we graduate and go our separate ways, I can just sit alone in my room and keep mixing them and keep releasing songs on SoundCloud for my mom.

<strong>Sheehan:</strong> Yeah, Danny's a mixing god.

<strong>Quirk:</strong> Danny took some of the recording classes at Georgetown, so he has access to the studio equipment.  He's gotten really good at it, not only recording but also mixing and editing the music offline, so that's a huge part of it, too, figuring out the recordings and the album artwork and all that stuff.  It's a huge thing to be able to do yourself.<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com/interview-with-georgetown-band-almeda/">Interview with Georgetown Band Almeda</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com"></a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thehoya.com/interview-with-georgetown-band-almeda/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>EDITORIAL: Our Closing Thoughts</title>
		<link>http://www.thehoya.com/editorial-our-closing-thoughts/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thehoya.com/editorial-our-closing-thoughts/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 09:30:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Opinion Editor]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Editorial]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion - Top]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[affordability]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[basketball]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Donald Trump]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[editorial]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[free speech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GUSA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[JT3]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[year in review]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thehoya.com/?p=23074309</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>In an eventful year for the university, Washington, D.C., and nation, topics from the protection of free speech to ensuring affordability to the basketball program to the university’s role in the current political landscape predominated campus dialogue. As the editorial board reflects on these issues, one thing is clear: It<a class="more-link" href="http://www.thehoya.com/editorial-our-closing-thoughts/">Read More</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com/editorial-our-closing-thoughts/">EDITORIAL: Our Closing Thoughts</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com"></a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[In an eventful year for the university, Washington, D.C., and nation, topics from the protection of free speech to ensuring affordability to the basketball program to the university’s role in the current political landscape predominated campus dialogue. As the editorial board reflects on these issues, one thing is clear: It is imperative for student voices to be heard and, more importantly, to be taken into account.

<strong>Defending Free Expression</strong>

This year, Georgetown made commendable strides toward defending free speech on campus. In March, administrators announced that the Free Speech and Expression Policy would be officially extended to faculty and would be included in the faculty handbook, making it easily available online.

However, the university still has a long way to go in protecting free speech. The most obvious examples are its limitations on student groups such as H*yas for Choice and Greek life organizations which are intended to discourage their on campus presence.

More importantly, however, the university’s free speech policy is vague and unclear to the student body. A range of contentious speakers this year — from Nonie Darwish, a noted critic of Islam and director of Former Muslims United, to Sebastian Gorka, a member of Hungarian neo-Nazi group Vitézi Rend — have also called into question the limits of the free speech policy.

In addition, the confusing free speech policy often creates incidents in which expression is muzzled without justification. For example, last year, students at the Georgetown University Law Center were prevented from campaigning for Sen. Bernie Sanders (I-Vt.) on campus; the university cited its tax-exempt status, saying that it could not engage in partisan political campaign activities. Incidents such as this, caused by the complexity of the policy, even earned Georgetown a spot on the Foundation for Individual Rights in Education’s list of the 10 worst colleges for free speech.

Both students and administrators must work to protect free speech by creating and adhering to a clear policy. Further, they must also ensure that free speech is not used to justify hate, but rather to promote constructive dialogue.

<strong>Assuring Affordability</strong>

Next year, tuition will for the first time exceed $50,000 — a 3.5 percent increase from 2016-17. Accounting for room, board and D.C.’s high living costs, the total annual cost for Georgetown now exceeds $70,000 for the average student.

The urgency of affordability is clear from this year’s Georgetown University Student Association presidential election, in which all tickets named affordability as the most pressing issue on campus. In polling by The Hoya, 33 percent of likely voters said that affordability was the most important topic of that race.

As the university raises tuition, it must be mindful of how this will discourage applicants from lower socioeconomic brackets. This impediment is particularly important given a report published in The New York Times in January, which revealed that 20.8 percent of Georgetown students come from families in the top 1 percent of the income scale.

Rising tuition most significantly disadvantages middle-class families, who can neither fully afford a Georgetown education nor qualify for full financial aid. The tuition hikes also hurt international students, who are allocated minimal financial aid as they are ineligible for federal funding.

Commendably, the university has taken strides toward greater tuition transparency this year. Due to efforts by the administration of former GUSA President Enushe Khan (MSB ’17) and Vice President Chris Fisk (COL ’17), administration devoted a town hall-style Hoya Roundtable specifically to the issue of tuition transparency.

However, transparency is insufficient. The administration must rein in tuition rates, as well as living costs, to make attendance more affordable.

Administrative efforts at transparency must also be accompanied by strides toward accountability. Students — the university’s most important stakeholders — should be included in discussions regarding tuition increases. As such, GUSA President Kamar Mack (COL ’19) and Vice President Jessica Andino (COL ’18) must advocate for student involvement in these discussions, as the Khan-Fisk administration did. Progress in cost-cutting spearheaded by Khan and Fisk this year, such as the inclusion of the price of 24 loads of laundry in room and board costs, demonstrates the potential of GUSA initiatives to achieve substantive change.

Going forward, the university should continue hosting Hoya Roundtables on tuition transparency. It must clarify the role of the Student Advisory Committee for the Provost — the central mechanism for student participation in the tuition-setting process — and ensure that the committee’s work is also transparent. Finally, administrators should work with the Mack-Andino administration to prioritize controlling the cost of Georgetown tuition. Only in this way can the university work toward affordability.

<strong>Rebuilding the Hoyas’ Prominence</strong>

In particular, this year was marked by upheaval within Georgetown’s basketball program. Ending the 2016-17 season with a 14-18 record, the Hoyas saw a drastic change when, after months of student frustration, the university fired Head Coach John Thompson III on March 23. On April 3, the university hired former Georgetown star player Patrick Ewing, who led the Hoyas to their only championship in 1984.

Though this personnel change is a step forward, the university must ensure it is accompanied by systemic shift. Ewing should assert his position as coach to create real change, despite his close relationship with former coach John Thompson Jr., who remains heavily, though unofficially, involved in the program.

Thompson Jr. — a legend of Georgetown basketball — is unlikely to cease involvement with the program anytime soon, nor should he; he is an important resource and mentor for Ewing.

Yet, to achieve meaningful change, Ewing must be the undisputed leader of his team. As such, he must seek to distance himself from the cultural issues — including the secrecy and the censorship of fans — that emerged during the tenure of Thompson III. Such change is needed to ensure Ewing does not repeat his predecessor’s mistakes.

<strong>Reaffirming Our National Role</strong>

Amid a year of national divisiveness, the university must operate in an entirely new context, one in which an action by President Donald Trump — whether it is the travel ban or the uncertain future of the Deferred Action for Childhood Arrivals program — can drastically affect the daily lives of Georgetown students.

Nevertheless, the role of the university remains the same: to protect its students and to foster an environment in which all students feel comfortable and can learn effectively. In the era of Trump, that will particularly include support for international student and students without documentation, who are most directly affected by the administration’s policies. The university has lived up to its obligation thus far, with President John J. DeGioia’s signing onto the amicus brief that condemned Trump’s travel ban; it must continue to do so.

As Georgetown students, we devote our time, efforts and money to this institution; in return we are promised not only an education, but also an ally within the school. The university must remember this obligation, and prioritize students’ safety, well-being and sense of security on their own campus.

Georgetown, for the most part, upholds its side of this promise. Yet, these are new times for everyone: Students and administrators all face the same uncertainty of this political moment. Together, we must reaffirm our role in support of each other and in our solidarity within the broader international context.<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com/editorial-our-closing-thoughts/">EDITORIAL: Our Closing Thoughts</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com"></a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thehoya.com/editorial-our-closing-thoughts/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
