<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title></title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.thehoya.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://www.thehoya.com</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 May 2017 20:59:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=4.1.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Movie Review: &#8216;Guardians of the Galaxy: Vol. 2&#8242;</title>
		<link>http://www.thehoya.com/movie-review-guardians-of-the-galaxy-vol-2/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thehoya.com/movie-review-guardians-of-the-galaxy-vol-2/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2017 17:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Guide Editor]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[The Guide]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[action]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adventure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chris pratt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[comedy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fantasy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[film]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[guardians]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[guardians of the galaxy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marvel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[movie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sequel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[superhero]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thehoya.com/?p=23074490</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>★★★★☆ In 2014, Marvel Studios released a new type of superhero film: one that was based on comedy and character development rather than action.  “Guardians of the Galaxy” dazzled fans with its witty script, celebrated cast and a ’70s soundtrack that perfectly tied the film together. With the success of<a class="more-link" href="http://www.thehoya.com/movie-review-guardians-of-the-galaxy-vol-2/">Read More</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com/movie-review-guardians-of-the-galaxy-vol-2/">Movie Review: &#8216;Guardians of the Galaxy: Vol. 2&#8242;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com"></a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[

★★★★☆

In 2014, Marvel Studios released a new type of superhero film: one that was based on comedy and character development rather than action.  “Guardians of the Galaxy” dazzled fans with its witty script, celebrated cast and a ’70s soundtrack that perfectly tied the film together. With the success of the film, Marvel quickly followed suit with “Ant-Man” in 2015, “Deadpool” in 2016 and, most recently, “Guardians of the Galaxy Vol. 2.” Marvel is continuing to produce comedic superhero films and plans to release “Deadpool 2” and “Ant-Man and the Wasp” in 2018. Although many Hollywood sequels often fall short of expectations, “Guardians of the Galaxy Vol. 2” comes close in matching the humor and charm of the original.<strong>
</strong>

The film continues to follow the adventures of the Guardians of the Galaxy — a group of extraterrestrial outcasts who use their powers to protect the universe from intergalactic threats — as they  uncover the mysterious relationship between their leader Peter Quill, played by Chris Pratt, and his father. Although the main story is centered on the reconnection of Quill and his father, there is a multitude of subplots that give the film a deeper sense of complexity than the original, introducing new allies and enemies for the Guardians.

With the return of all five members of the main team — Chris Pratt, Zoe Saldana, Dave Bautista, Bradley Cooper and Vin Diesel — and the additions of Sylvester Stallone and Kurt Russell, the film is able to minimize the unfortunate losses of original cast members John C. Reilly and Benicio del Toro. Reilly played Rhomann Dey, a friend of Peter Quill’s, and del Toro played the Collector, a powerful Elder of the Universe . Although Dey and the Collector were not very instrumental to the plot of the original film, the characters certainly added depth to the “Guardians of the Galaxy” universe — and of course, Reilly and del Toro’s comedic chops were put to good use.

Despite the departures of Reilly and del Toro, the chemistry between the cast members remains flawless, and is a feature of  the “Guardians of the Galaxy” series that makes it so enjoyable to watch. Throughout the film, the interactions between characters seem natural and are a constant source of entertainment, especially as the Guardians exchange hilarious insults with each other — and their enemies.  “Guardians of the Galaxy Vol. 2” enhances existing character development, building on the team’s lively dynamic established in the first film and deepening the relationships between the Guardians, particularly as the superheroes face new challenges and threats of betrayal.

Although all of the actors deliver excellent performances, Dave Bautista upstages the rest of the cast with his depiction of Drax the Destroyer, whose oblivious yet deadpan sense of humor is one of the highlights of the film.

In addition to developing captivating relationships between characters, “Guardians of the Galaxy Vol. 2” is extremely successful in incorporating comedy throughout its script — a feat that defined the original. The film delights audiences with its unrefined yet entertaining sense of humor,  distinctive to movies like “Deadpool” and “Guardians of the Galaxy.” Gunn succeeds in bringing more comedy to the new film, making “Guardians of the Galaxy Vol. 2” even more upbeat than the original. Ultimately, he creates a film that provides audiences with more opportunities to laugh than even recent comedy films.

The one clear, and very disappointing, flaw in “Guardians of the Galaxy Vol. 2” is its soundtrack.  “Guardians of the Galaxy: Awesome Mix Vol. 1,” the album that accompanied the original film, is arguably one of the greatest soundtracks of all time, as illustrated by its No. 1 position on the U.S. Billboard 200 chart for best album. Although “Guardians of the Galaxy Vol. 2” features songs by beloved artists, like Electric Light Orchestra, Fleetwood Mac, George Harrison and Cheap Trick, the film’s soundtrack is unable to capture the playful essence of the music of the original.

Gunn’s “Guardians of the Galaxy Vol. 2” is an entertaining and humorous film that tells a compelling story, seamlessly picking up just two months after where the original ends. Given the critical acclaim of the first film, “Guardians of the Galaxy Vol. 2” was expected to meet tremendously high standards, and surprisingly, succeeds in being nearly as good as the original, avoiding Hollywood’s predictable sequel slump. The film leaves fans feeling hopeful and excited for the upcoming third film in the franchise, “Guardians of the Galaxy Vol. 3,” also to be written and directed by Gunn — and establishes the series as one of Marvel’s finest works to date.<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com/movie-review-guardians-of-the-galaxy-vol-2/">Movie Review: &#8216;Guardians of the Galaxy: Vol. 2&#8242;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com"></a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thehoya.com/movie-review-guardians-of-the-galaxy-vol-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>VIEWPOINT: Valuing Philosophy in Foreign Policy</title>
		<link>http://www.thehoya.com/viewpoint-valuing-philosophy-in-foreign-policy/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thehoya.com/viewpoint-valuing-philosophy-in-foreign-policy/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2017 03:30:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Opinion Editor]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion - Top]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Donald Trump]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[foreign policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[philosophy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[state department]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thehoya.com/?p=23074507</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>After just over 100 days, the White House faces clear foreign policy challenges. Real estate mogul-turned-President Donald Trump has tried his hand at addressing various international crises, authorizing a retaliatory strike on the Syrian government, ramping up airstrikes against the Islamic State group and dropping the "Mother of All Bombs"<a class="more-link" href="http://www.thehoya.com/viewpoint-valuing-philosophy-in-foreign-policy/">Read More</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com/viewpoint-valuing-philosophy-in-foreign-policy/">VIEWPOINT: Valuing Philosophy in Foreign Policy</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com"></a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[After just over 100 days, the White House faces clear foreign policy challenges. Real estate mogul-turned-President Donald Trump has tried his hand at addressing various international crises, authorizing a retaliatory strike on the Syrian government, ramping up airstrikes against the Islamic State group and dropping the "Mother of All Bombs" on IS targets in Afghanistan, to name a few endeavors. Despite these efforts, the administration has thus far failed to alter the course of the Syrian civil war and has increased the number of civilian casualties in Iraq, with <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/national-security/after-reports-of-civilian-deaths-us-military-struggles-to-defend-air-operations-in-war-against-militants/2017/04/10/838e950a-1893-11e7-855e-4824bbb5d748_story.html?utm_term=.5bb5e6143c6f">nearly 500 civilian deaths</a> in Iraq and Syria in March 2017 alone. Moreover, the administration has inched toward a <a href="http://www.cnn.com/2017/05/15/politics/north-korea-trump-defiance/">potential nuclear confrontation</a> in East Asia.

What could the White House be getting wrong? With his all-star team of generals, such as Defense Secretary James Mattis and national security adviser H.R. McMaster, and allegedly adept problem-solvers, Secretary of State Rex Tillerson and son-in-law Jared Kushner, Trump should have no trouble achieving key foreign policy goals. While one could argue that the general lack of expertise in the White House and failure to <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2017/04/27/us/politics/state-department-diplomats-tillerson.html?_r=1">staff crucial posts in Foggy Bottom</a> have limited the State Department’s ability to achieve its goals, I believe that what these decision-makers lack is the right frame of mind.

Trump has appointed business leaders and soldiers to address the world’s challenges. What the State Department needs are philosophers.

This is not a call for the State Department to replace its highest-ranking officials with the top scholars of philosophy from America’s top universities. But imagine if it did. Ethicists studying the great debates of the 20th century could help determine America’s priorities and assess the costs of its actions abroad. Those who provide solutions to the world's most challenging thought experiments may be able to tackle the dilemmas we face in regions such as the Middle East.

In a geopolitical landscape where disinformation threatens states almost as much as military power, epistemologists would play a unique role. Who can better dismantle the modern weapon of “fake news” than those well-versed in knowledge, and how it is consumed and transmitted by people? Perhaps clearer definitions of information and how it is understood could function as tools of information warfare. Moreover, the demand for these minds is pressing given recent cries of America's decline as a moral superpower.

America faces uncertainty due to issues such as global climate change and security challenges brought about by emerging technologies and cyberspace. Today’s questions are often less concerned with scientific data and more so with answers to how humans ought to grapple with scientific realities. Philosophers of science and technology can provide valuable insight into how to cope with scientific revolutions and paradigm shifts.

For example, increasing incidences of computer and internet fraud present security threats for American citizens and companies both at home and abroad. The deployment of drones, also known as “killer robots,” and the prevalence of small arms in civil wars raise questions about human interaction with technology and its effect on conflict. Policymakers and scientists must be involved in such conversations, but so must the thinkers engaged in understanding long-term consequences of these foreign policy issues.

Destroying terrorists is another Trumpian promise yet to fully materialize in the first few months of the presidency. Targeting terror cells and lone wolves, however, involves much more than bombing campaigns and immigration restrictions. In fact, understanding political psychology may be an effective complement in countering radicalization. Addressing the deeper questions, such as the nature of human agency or the effect of religious beliefs on human behavior, will contribute to these broad counterterrorism efforts.

Trump’s approach to foreign policy has been simple. It requires few words to be understood: America will be rich. America will be strong. America will win. Our president’s favorite taglines contradict the reality and complexity of deep questions with long-term consequences.

Perhaps it is too much to ask for to have Socrates’ philosopher-king in the White House or the State Department. But the United States will never be able to maintain its position as an active global power in the 21st century without professionals focused on deep philosophical questions. If the Trump administration wishes to truly be great in this regard, it ought to begin asking the big questions or welcome those who do.

<strong><em>Matt Hinson</em></strong> is a senior in the School of Foreign Service.<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com/viewpoint-valuing-philosophy-in-foreign-policy/">VIEWPOINT: Valuing Philosophy in Foreign Policy</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com"></a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thehoya.com/viewpoint-valuing-philosophy-in-foreign-policy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Voyage Through JFK&#8217;s Legacy</title>
		<link>http://www.thehoya.com/a-voyage-through-jfks-legacy/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thehoya.com/a-voyage-through-jfks-legacy/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 17:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Guide Editor]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Features]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Guide]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[american]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[exhibit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Georgetown icons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[history]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[icon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[JKF]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kennedy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[legacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[museum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[presidency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[president]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quotes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smithsonian]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[united states]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thehoya.com/?p=23074480</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>The Smithsonian American Art Museum recently unveiled its newest exhibit, “American Visionary: John F. Kennedy’s Life and Times,” a fascinating photo gallery that explores and celebrates the life and legacy of the 35th president. Visitors might ask, what exactly is it that makes Kennedy an “American visionary,” and an international<a class="more-link" href="http://www.thehoya.com/a-voyage-through-jfks-legacy/">Read More</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com/a-voyage-through-jfks-legacy/">A Voyage Through JFK&#8217;s Legacy</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com"></a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[

The Smithsonian American Art Museum recently unveiled its newest exhibit, “American Visionary: John F. Kennedy’s Life and Times,” a fascinating photo gallery that explores and celebrates the life and legacy of the 35th president. Visitors might ask, what exactly is it that makes Kennedy an “American visionary,” and an international symbol for the country’s character? Was it his natural rebelliousness, his genius, his handsome face or his witty charm?

From the moment he was elected to office, Kennedy fascinated the American public. He was considered a beacon of hope for Americans who had just experienced World War I. From his youthful charisma to his sheer intellect, Kennedy embodied and shaped a confident and progressive America.

Stephanie Stebich, the Smithsonian American Art Museum’s director, and John Jacobs, the exhibit’s coordinating curator, introduced Lawrence Schiller, an esteemed photojournalist who collaborated with Stephen Kennedy Smith, Kennedy’s nephew, to turn the exhibit into a reality.

Schiller was a photographer on Kennedy’s campaign trail, and his dedication to telling Kennedy’s story shined through his insightful and captivating knowledge of the president and explanation of the meaning behind the exhibit’s photographs.

The exhibit brings together 77 images, collected from a total of 34,000 images found in the John F. Kennedy Presidential Library and Museum, John F. Kennedy Library Foundation and private collections from the Kennedy family archives. The photographs are accompanied by quotes on each wall, meant to illustrate yet another dimension of Kennedy’s life.



The early 1960s marked a golden age for photojournalism in America; Kennedy’s administration was largely captured through photography, especially given the absence of videographers at the time. As a campaign photographer, Lawrence Schiller described his job as simply having to “observe and lift the camera at the right moment.”

Schiller stated that no single politician was photographed more than Kennedy, and that the abundance of images of his family, political meetings and social gatherings emulated the significant generational change — and a new America.

Each room in the exhibit was assigned a different title: “The Making of JFK,” “The Road to the White House” and lastly, “The New Frontier.” In each room, the photographs were organized chronologically and thematically to authentically illustrate the story surrounding Kennedy’s election, personal life and legacy.

Throughout the tour, Schiller treated visitors to short anecdotes about the president and his family, lending a personal touch to the already poignant atmosphere of the rooms. For example, according to Schiller, in the book “JFK: A Vision for America,” the Kennedys asked only that the last image in the book be changed to the iconic photograph of Kennedy walking alone on the beach.



Schiller continued to captivate and entertain the group with stories of Kennedy’s younger years, from his early beginnings as a journalist at Harvard University to his later involvement in politics.

Kennedy strongly believed that the arts were essential to a vital democracy and recognized the importance of photographs in conveying his message to voters. With the media on his side, he could successfully and directly communicate with the public and his supporters, and gain recognition for his causes, like the Peace Corps, the space program and legislation on civil rights and immigration.

The exhibit comes to a close with a section commemorating Kennedy’s assassination in Dallas. This part of the exhibit, unlike the rest, does not contain many photographs.

“Less is more; we wanted to be able to tell the story in the simplest way,” Schiller said.

This section serves as a reminder that, although Kennedy’s legacy still resonates with us today, his final visions were not completely realized during his presidency.

Although this exhibit was organized to commemorate Kennedy’s life and work, its relevance in today’s political environment has become a part of its role and significance. As guests marveled at Kennedy’s legacy, they reflected on how it has become increasingly difficult to identify figures from either political party that embody Kennedy’s persona and influence.

As the exhibit poetically and aesthetically demonstrates, the Kennedy administration brought a sense of warmth and sophistication to the White House. Kennedy and his family instilled a sense of promise into the eyes of previously hopeless Americans. For all of their lofty goals, Schiller and the other collaborators and curators successfully shed light on the “human puzzle” that is Kennedy, which has continued to attract so many people to investigate his life and legacy.

<em>The “American Visionary: John F Kennedy’s Life and Times” exhibit will be on display at the Smithsonian American Art Museum until September 17.</em><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com/a-voyage-through-jfks-legacy/">A Voyage Through JFK&#8217;s Legacy</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com"></a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thehoya.com/a-voyage-through-jfks-legacy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>GUPD Investigates Anti-Semitic Graffiti Near Jewish Gathering Space</title>
		<link>http://www.thehoya.com/gupd-investigates-anti-semitic-graffiti-near-makom-jewish-gathering-space/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thehoya.com/gupd-investigates-anti-semitic-graffiti-near-makom-jewish-gathering-space/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 18:41:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[City News Editor]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Campus News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News - Top]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[anti-semitic graffiti]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[anti-Semitism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bias-related incident]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chief of Police Jay Gruber]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[howard gray]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Makóm Jewish Gathering Place]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vice President for Student Affairs Todd Olson]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thehoya.com/?p=23074463</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Anti-Semitic graffiti was found in a public restroom next to the Makóm Jewish gathering space in Leavey Center Saturday morning. The graffiti, which includes a death threat, has been classified as a bias-related incident. The Georgetown University Police Department is currently investigating the incident, according to Senior Director for Strategic<a class="more-link" href="http://www.thehoya.com/gupd-investigates-anti-semitic-graffiti-near-makom-jewish-gathering-space/">Read More</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com/gupd-investigates-anti-semitic-graffiti-near-makom-jewish-gathering-space/">GUPD Investigates Anti-Semitic Graffiti Near Jewish Gathering Space</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com"></a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[

Anti-Semitic graffiti was found in a public restroom next to the Makóm Jewish gathering space in Leavey Center Saturday morning.

The graffiti, which includes a death threat, has been classified as a bias-related incident. The Georgetown University Police Department is currently investigating the incident, according to Senior Director for Strategic Communications Rachel Pugh.

According to a campuswide email from Interim Vice President for Mission and Ministry Rev. Howard Gray, S.J., and Vice President for Student Affairs Todd Olson today, a student found the graffiti written on a sticker on the door of a bathroom stall.

GUPD will increase patrols around campus and coordinate with the Metropolitan Police Department to surveil the neighborhood.

Matthew Sachs (COL ‘20) who first reported the graffiti to GUPD, said he discovered the note Saturday morning (Full disclosure: Sachs is a staff writer for The Hoya).
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">“At first I looked at the writing and thought, ‘This is totally unacceptable.’ But, I soon realized how incredibly disturbing and hateful this was to me and the people I shared it with,” Sachs wrote in an email to The Hoya. “I truly hope that in the future, our students can learn to accept all faiths and religious groups and uphold the honor and respect that Georgetown prides itself on.”</span></p>
Gray and Olson condemned the graffiti in their email.

“As a Catholic and Jesuit university, we are committed to fostering a community that is welcoming to people of all faiths and that values diversity, inclusion and respect,” they wrote. “This act of anti-Semitism and hate is unacceptable, antithetical to what we stand for as a university, and has no place on our campus.”

The graffiti is the latest in <a href="http://www.thehoya.com/two-bias-related-attacks-reported/">a series of bias-related incidents</a> reported on campus over the past year, and mirrors a <a href="http://www.thehoya.com/district-sees-increase-in-reported-hate-related-crimes/">rise in hate-related crimes</a> in Washington, D.C.

In late March, GUPD investigated two separate cases of vandalism targeting Jewish, Muslim and Hindu communities in New South Hall and Village C West, where two swastikas were found scratched scratched into the interior walls of an elevator. The swastikas were painted over by the following morning.

Two separate bias reports were reported the week of March 20 regarding incidents of Muslim and Hindu flyers being ripped down and vandalized from chaplain-in-residence bulletin boards.

The incident also follows a semester marked by other challenges for Jewish student groups. On April 24, International Holocaust Remembrance Day, organizers of the Cyber Project conference in the School of Foreign Service Masters program invited White House deputy assistant Sebastian Gorka to speak on a panel on cybersecurity and propaganda. Gorka's appearance was protested by Jewish, Muslim and LGBT students opposing his positions on the Muslim community, religious profiling, and alleged affiliations with a Hungarian neo-Nazi connected group, Vitézi Rend.

Gray and Olson reaffirmed the university’s commitment to diversity and inclusivity in the email today.

“We stand with our Jewish community and any campus community that experiences acts of bias,” they wrote. “Together we condemn acts of hate and celebrate our global community, which is made stronger by our religious, cultural and international diversity.”

Pugh said that anyone with information about the incident should contact GUPD.

<em>This is a developing story. The post will be updated as more information becomes available.</em><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com/gupd-investigates-anti-semitic-graffiti-near-makom-jewish-gathering-space/">GUPD Investigates Anti-Semitic Graffiti Near Jewish Gathering Space</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com"></a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thehoya.com/gupd-investigates-anti-semitic-graffiti-near-makom-jewish-gathering-space/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Second-Year Georgetown Law Student Dies</title>
		<link>http://www.thehoya.com/georgetown-law-student-dies/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thehoya.com/georgetown-law-student-dies/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2017 00:11:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Campus News Editor]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[City News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News - Top]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Destinee McCulley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[georgetown law center]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gulc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[law school]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thehoya.com/?p=23074456</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Destinee McCulley (LAW ’18) was found dead April 28 in her off-campus apartment, Georgetown University Law Center Dean William Treanor announced in an email to the law school community on April 29. McCulley was in her second year at Georgetown Law and graduated with honors from California Baptist University in 2015, where she<a class="more-link" href="http://www.thehoya.com/georgetown-law-student-dies/">Read More</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com/georgetown-law-student-dies/">Second-Year Georgetown Law Student Dies</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com"></a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[Destinee McCulley (LAW ’18) was found dead April 28 in her off-campus apartment, Georgetown University Law Center Dean William Treanor announced in an email to the law school community on April 29.

McCulley was in her second year at Georgetown Law and graduated with honors from California Baptist University in 2015, where she studied political science and philosophy.

McCulley was also the managing editor of the Georgetown Journal of Gender and the Law, according to her LinkedIn page.

An initial investigation by the Metropolitan Police Department found no evidence of foul play, according to Treanor.

In his email, Treanor said McCulley was a beloved member of the community.

“Her friends remember her as intellectually gifted, relentlessly dedicated to serving the less fortunate and making the world better for others, and blessed with an infectious smile, a genuine kindness and, in their beautiful words, ‘a capacity to love that is rare in this world,’” Treanor wrote.

The Law Center is offering professional and spiritual counseling resources to students. Treanor urged any students looking for support to <a href="https://www.law.georgetown.edu/campus-life/advising-counseling/personal-counseling/index.cfm">schedule an appointment with Counseling and Psychiatric Services</a> or to <a href="https://www.law.georgetown.edu/campus-life/spiritual-life/staff.cfm">seek support from Campus Ministry</a>.

<em>This post will be updated as more information becomes available.</em><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com/georgetown-law-student-dies/">Second-Year Georgetown Law Student Dies</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com"></a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thehoya.com/georgetown-law-student-dies/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>2017 Commencement Speakers to Include Journalists, Media Figures</title>
		<link>http://www.thehoya.com/2017-commencement-speakers-announced/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thehoya.com/2017-commencement-speakers-announced/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 21:02:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Campus News Editor]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Campus News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News - Top]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[buzzfeed]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commencement 2017]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gregory coleman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nate silver]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thehoya.com/?p=23074447</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Nate Silver, editor-in-chief of statistics blog FiveThirtyEight, and Gregory Gerard Coleman (GSB ’76), president of BuzzFeed, are among the 12 speakers scheduled to address graduates at this year’s commencement ceremonies from May 18 to 21, the university announced today. The university will hold separate graduation ceremonies for each school, beginning<a class="more-link" href="http://www.thehoya.com/2017-commencement-speakers-announced/">Read More</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com/2017-commencement-speakers-announced/">2017 Commencement Speakers to Include Journalists, Media Figures</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com"></a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[

Nate Silver, editor-in-chief of statistics blog FiveThirtyEight, and Gregory Gerard Coleman (GSB ’76), president of BuzzFeed, are among the 12 speakers scheduled to address graduates at this year’s commencement ceremonies from May 18 to 21, the university announced today.

The university will hold separate graduation ceremonies for each school, beginning with the McCourt School of Public Policy on May 18 and ending with the Law Center’s ceremony May 21.

University President John J. DeGioia wrote in a statement on the Georgetown website he looks forward to the wisdom these speakers have to impart upon the Class of 2017.

“Commencement is one of the most special moments for our university community each year," DeGioia wrote. "We are honored to welcome a number of distinguished individuals to our campus this May and we look forward to the ways in which their insights will challenge and inspire each of our graduates as they prepare to leave our Hilltop and make an impact on our world."

Silver, who will receive an honorary Doctor of Humane Letters degree from the university, is scheduled to speak at the School of Continuing Studies commencement ceremony May 19. A statistician and writer best known for analyzing sports and elections, Silver was named one of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Time_100">The World's 100 Most Influential People</a> by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Time_(magazine)">Time</a> in 2009 after he successfully called the outcomes of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_States_presidential_election,_2008">2008 U.S. presidential election</a> in 49 of the 50 states.

Coleman will receive an honorary Doctor of Humane Letters degree from the university and is scheduled to address the McDonough School of Business undergraduate commencement ceremony May 20. Coleman was appointed president of BuzzFeed in 2014, after serving as president of The Huffington Post until 2011 and Criteo, a digital marketing company, until 2014.

Coleman received his MBA from New York University, where he currently works as an adjunct professor on digital marketing in the Stern School of Business.

Additional commencement speakers include Sr. Mary Scullion, R.S.M., executive director and president of Project HOME, a nonprofit organization that provides housing and services to chronically homeless men and women, who will address the College on May 20; James H. Shelton III, president of Facebook founder Mark Zuckerberg's Chan Zuckerberg Education and Chan Zuckerberg Initiative, who will address the School of Nursing and Health Studies on May 20; and Washington Post columnist and London School of Economics visiting professor of practice Anne Applebaum, who will address the School of Foreign Service on May 20.

All of the commencement ceremonies will be available for livestreaming at the university commencement website.<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com/2017-commencement-speakers-announced/">2017 Commencement Speakers to Include Journalists, Media Figures</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com"></a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thehoya.com/2017-commencement-speakers-announced/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>LETTER TO THE EDITOR: After 52 Years, A Confession</title>
		<link>http://www.thehoya.com/letter-to-the-editor-after-52-years-a-confession/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thehoya.com/letter-to-the-editor-after-52-years-a-confession/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 02:28:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Opinion Editor]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion - Top]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[healy clock hands]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[letter to the editor]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thehoya.com/?p=23074429</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Dear Editor: In the fall of 1965, I was a freshman in the Georgetown College living on the fourth floor of Old North. Another freshman, who shall remain unnamed, and I decided to steal the hands from the clock on Healy Tower. We went up through the attic of Healy<a class="more-link" href="http://www.thehoya.com/letter-to-the-editor-after-52-years-a-confession/">Read More</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com/letter-to-the-editor-after-52-years-a-confession/">LETTER TO THE EDITOR: After 52 Years, A Confession</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com"></a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[

Dear Editor:

In the fall of 1965, I was a freshman in the Georgetown College living on the fourth floor of Old North. Another freshman, who shall remain unnamed, and I decided to steal the hands from the clock on Healy Tower. We went up through the attic of Healy Hall after picking the lock on the attic door. We were able to open a small door on the face of the clock. This allowed us to remove the hands of the clock. Once we had them, we did not know what to do with them. But then we were struck with a brilliant idea. We took the larger of the two hands, wrapped it in tissue paper and placed it in a long flower box. We then had the box with the clock hand delivered to the new dean of discipline with a note saying, "Dear Dean: Here is a gift from the freshman class of the College to let you know that we are always willing to give you a hand.” The dean was very pleased to receive our gift, which he thought was a mace, a medieval symbol of authority. He had the clock hand mounted on his office wall in a place of honor for all to see. Several weeks later, the dean was in his office working when a janitor came in to clean. The janitor looked at the mace and asked, "Father, why do you have the hand of the Healy clock on your wall?" History does not record the dean's response, but suffice it to say that he was not happy. After this story got around the campus, he was even less happy. Fortunately, I was never apprehended. And by now, I hope the statute of limitations has run out on my crime. My friend was caught and subsequently suspended from school. But he never gave me up, for which I will be forever grateful to him.

<em>Mark G. Griffin (CAS</em><em> ’69, LAW ’73)</em><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com/letter-to-the-editor-after-52-years-a-confession/">LETTER TO THE EDITOR: After 52 Years, A Confession</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com"></a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thehoya.com/letter-to-the-editor-after-52-years-a-confession/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Two-Thirds of University Email Accounts Targeted by Phishing Scam</title>
		<link>http://www.thehoya.com/university-email-accounts-targeted-by-phishing-scam/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thehoya.com/university-email-accounts-targeted-by-phishing-scam/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2017 21:32:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Campus News Editor]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News - Top]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[phishing scam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[university information services]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thehoya.com/?p=23074407</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>About 14,000 Georgetown email accounts were targeted within an hour by a widespread phishing scam involving fake Google Docs invitations Wednesday, leading some students and faculty to inadvertently compromise their accounts, according to Georgetown Chief Information Officer Judd Nicholson. Two-thirds of Georgetown email accounts were targeted by the nationwide scam, making it the<a class="more-link" href="http://www.thehoya.com/university-email-accounts-targeted-by-phishing-scam/">Read More</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com/university-email-accounts-targeted-by-phishing-scam/">Two-Thirds of University Email Accounts Targeted by Phishing Scam</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com"></a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[About 14,000 Georgetown email accounts were targeted within an hour by a widespread phishing scam involving fake Google Docs invitations Wednesday, leading some students and faculty to inadvertently compromise their accounts, according to Georgetown Chief Information Officer Judd Nicholson.

Two-thirds of Georgetown email accounts were targeted by the nationwide scam, making it the largest hacking campaign affecting the university in recent memory, according to Chief Information Security Officer Joseph Lee. Hackers successfully gained access to as many as 1 million total Gmail accounts, though a Google spokesperson said the hackers were only able to access contact information of victims, not their personal emails.

Though it is not unusual for the university to encounter smaller phishing attempts, Lee said Wednesday's campaign affected significantly more than past campaigns.

<strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">"We get them all the time, and it’s not just us, every university gets them," Lee said. "But t<strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">his one is fairly unique, in that it impacted about two-thirds of the university community."</span></strong></span></strong>

The scam involved emails inviting recipients to open a Google Doc, which, if opened, allowed hackers to gain access to recipients' Google accounts. The scam replicated itself by sending the same link to users' contacts. The emails, sent by hackers, were disguised to look as if they were sent from legitimate university email accounts — a practice known as "spoofing."

The scam emails were widely reported Wednesday afternoon, including at universities and major media organizations. Information technology experts said the scam was nearly impossible to detect, because it contained a real Google link and did not contain red flags, like spelling or formatting errors. In a statement posted to Twitter at 1:08 p.m., Google said it was investigating the scam and advised users not to open any unexpected Google invitations and to report any scam emails they receive.

To shut down the campaign, Google removed the fraudulent pages and applications and disabled the responsible Google accounts. The company resolved the scam within an hour, and updated its security features after the campaign to prevent similar scams in the future.

Lee said the university was working on steps to counter the hack and alerting affected Georgetown users when Google came out with their own fix.

"A<strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">s we were impacted, just like many other companies and universities were impacted, we were trying to figure out what steps to take and what instructions we needed to give to our university community," Lee said. "But as soon as we started doing that, Google took its own action."</span></strong>

The purpose of the scam remains unclear. Users initially feared the hackers would be capable of accessing the victims' emails or revoking the victim's access to their own account by changing the password, before Google's investigation discovered this was not the case, according to a Reddit threat discussing the scam shortly after it was discovered.

People affected by the scam were initially advised to revoke permissions for the false Google Docs program by accessing their account security settings. Google said Wednesday evening that no further action by users was necessary.

Nicholson said that in spite of occasional security breaches, the university email system has stronger security protections than most personal email accounts.

"<span style="font-weight: 400;">We have a multi-layered security approach for information within the university," Nicholson said. "We have spam control, we have firewalls that offer some level of protection. We also watch the borders, to ensure that if there is some malicious traffic coming in, that we can keep it out."</span>

<em>This post has been updated.</em><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com/university-email-accounts-targeted-by-phishing-scam/">Two-Thirds of University Email Accounts Targeted by Phishing Scam</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com"></a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thehoya.com/university-email-accounts-targeted-by-phishing-scam/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Theater Review: &#8216;Fun Home&#8217;</title>
		<link>http://www.thehoya.com/theater-review-fun-home/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thehoya.com/theater-review-fun-home/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 10:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Guide Editor]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Arts & Entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Guide]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arts and entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[comedy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[musical]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[national theatre]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the guide]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[theater]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[theater review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[visual and performing arts]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thehoya.com/?p=23074351</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Directed by Sam Gold and based on Alison Bechdel’s award-winning autobiographical graphic novel, Tony Award-winning musical “Fun Home” made its Washington, D.C. premiere April 18 at the National Theatre. The musical delivers a striking study of human relationships, particularly those between father and daughter, as its protagonist Alison, played by<a class="more-link" href="http://www.thehoya.com/theater-review-fun-home/">Read More</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com/theater-review-fun-home/">Theater Review: &#8216;Fun Home&#8217;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com"></a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[

Directed by Sam Gold and based on Alison Bechdel’s award-winning autobiographical graphic novel, Tony Award-winning musical “Fun Home” made its Washington, D.C. premiere April 18 at the National Theatre. The musical delivers a striking study of human relationships, particularly those between father and daughter, as its protagonist Alison, played by Kate Shindle, struggles to determine how alike she and her father are. They both grew up in the same small Pennsylvania town. They both love literature. And they are, as Alison eventually learns, both gay.

As she attempts to sort through her father’s story — and by extension, her own — Alison revisits memories of her childhood as Small Alison, played by Alessandra Baldacchino, and her freshman year at Oberlin College as Medium Alison, played by Abby Corrigan. Throughout this personal exploration, composer Jeanine Tesori’s music, replete with reprises that tie the present to the past, as well as the scenic design by David Zinn carry the audience down the winding memory lane. As Alison struggles to piece together her family’s history into a coherent narrative, she encounters her own blind spots and uncertainties.

The stunning set of “Fun Home” mirrors Alison’s personal journey throughout the play. Starting as a jumble of obscure, old-fashioned objects — Victorian-era furniture, an old silver teapot, a door with a sign marked “Gay Union” taped to it — punctuated by Alison’s present-day writing desk, the seemingly randomly designed set begins to take clearer form as she starts to unravel her own memories, with each recollection becoming more elaborate. In the final scene, as Alison walks into her family’s old living room in a final memory, the mismatch of couches and piano have become a full-fledged, elaborately decorated interior: Alison’s past as she lived it, in vivid detail.

Alison’s rediscovery of her past as she attempts to understand her family’s story is intertwined with her own journey of self-discovery and early conflicts over her own identity: arguments with her father about wearing dresses as a young child, identifying with a butch delivery woman in a luncheonette and her first sexual encounter at college.

Despite its utter sincerity, “Fun Home" remains keenly aware of the irony of its own story — the title refers to a funeral home, called the “Fun Home” by young children who grow up with death as a fact of life. There is a continuous emphasis on the intersection of the mundane and the grave — Alison’s father catches his children hiding in a casket as they cheerfully rehearse a commercial for the family business, for example — which drifts from hilarious to haunting as tragedy becomes personal. All the while, Alison attempts to mine meaning from the smallest details of her childhood recollections in her hunt for answers.

It is easy to see why “Fun Home” won five of the 12 Tony Awards for which it was nominated, including Best Musical: Its music is stunning and well-placed. More impressively, the impulse for Broadway theatrics never overwhelms the show’s true strength — its story and the realness of its characters. Shindle is captivating as the smart and funny but haunted Alison, while the three younger cast members — Baldacchino as Small Alison, and Pierson Salvador and Lennon Nate Hammond as her brothers Christian and John — never fail to delight.

Perhaps the most powerful performance is delivered by Robert Petkoff, who portrays Alison’s father, Bruce, a character who easily wins over the audience even as Alison herself struggles with her feelings toward him. Bruce and Alison’s duets, which at times take place with Bruce in the past and Alison in the present, are the strongest parts of a show that has few noticeable weaknesses, illustrating the immense vocal and acting talents of the cast.

Performed without an intermission, “Fun Home” allows the audience to reflect on the undecided fate of the protagonist: Alison is ultimately left to draw her own conclusions about her family and herself.

Early in the show, Small Alison and Bruce fight about a school assignment, as he attempts to teach her to draw a realistic landscape and she resists with a cartoon depiction. “Maps show you what is simple and true,” Alison sings, but their conflict gives a more realistic picture: What you see depends on who you are, and Bruce’s story may never be truly understood by Alison, no matter how alike — or different — she and her father are.

“FUN HOME” runs at the National Theatre through May 13. Tickets are priced $48 — $98 and are available at thenationaldc.org.<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com/theater-review-fun-home/">Theater Review: &#8216;Fun Home&#8217;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com"></a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thehoya.com/theater-review-fun-home/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>VIEWPOINT: The Dilemma of the Underpaid Adjunct</title>
		<link>http://www.thehoya.com/viewpoint-dilemma-underpaid-adjunct/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thehoya.com/viewpoint-dilemma-underpaid-adjunct/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 01:15:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Opinion Editor]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion - Top]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adjunct]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[equal pay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tenure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[viewpoint]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women's and gender studies]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thehoya.com/?p=23074387</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>With love and regret, I am saying farewell to Georgetown after 21 wonderful years on the faculty of the women’s and gender studies program and a recent, shiny Silver Vicennial Medal for my two decades of service. I will miss you all and, in particular, my beloved Hoya athletes, so<a class="more-link" href="http://www.thehoya.com/viewpoint-dilemma-underpaid-adjunct/">Read More</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com/viewpoint-dilemma-underpaid-adjunct/">VIEWPOINT: The Dilemma of the Underpaid Adjunct</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com"></a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[With love and regret, I am saying farewell to Georgetown after 21 wonderful years on the faculty of the women’s and gender studies program and a recent, shiny Silver Vicennial Medal for my two decades of service. I will miss you all and, in particular, my beloved Hoya athletes, so many of whom took my popular “Athletics and Gender” class or my “Intro to Women’s Studies” class. Yet, the women’s and gender studies program remains in the good hands of its devoted chair, You-Me Park, to whom I owe so many teaching years here at Georgetown — years rich in culture, community, the love and respect of co-workers and the pleasure of campus life.

So, at the top of my game, with 15 books published and a recent exhibit at the Library of Congress, why leave the Hilltop? The answer is painful: <a href="http://www.thehoya.com/editorial-value-faculty-protect-union/">Like many non-tenured faculty</a>, I can no longer afford to live in Washington, D.C. Since 1996, I have cheerfully combined two half-time appointments, at both Georgetown and The George Washington University. Neither school offers tenure or promotion for faculty in women’s studies, which at both institutions is an underfunded program<em>, </em>rather than a department<em>. </em>For almost a decade now, to make ends meet, I have taught a load of eight courses per year, paid either per course or half of what I would earn in a tenure-track position. Now, thanks to budget cuts, I have no benefits at either institution and pay out of pocket for medical expenses at age 55.

Stories like mine are common among adjunct professors: We love what we do, you love us and we energetically work at two or three jobs until we wear ourselves out. The moral dilemma is that in the underfunded area of women’s studies, I teach<em> </em>the history of equal pay for equal work, while not receiving it myself. By continuing to accept a pay rate that is not on par with those who teach less and publish less, I can no longer call myself a good feminist role model to the young women who constitute the majority of Georgetown undergraduates. As an underpaid adjunct in an underfunded program, I can no longer sit idly by.

I have sought solutions and sent proposals, but we simply are not seeing the financial dedication to the women’s history field that I assumed would be the case by 2017. Now, with my mother growing older, I have an invitation to come live and write at my family home in California, where I can continue to be a consultant archivist to the Smithsonian Institution and the Library of Congress while lecturing part time in the University of California system. My 79-year-old mother, my 21-year-old niece and I will be three generations, in one house, committed to the production of art and activism around women’s lives. With my all-too-common story in mind, I invite you to consider the need for change in our institutions, so that a living wage is within the reach of all teaching faculty who gave up safer career choices to inspire future generations.

<strong><em>Bonnie J. Morris</em></strong><em> is an adjunct assistant professor in the women’</em><em>s and gender studies program.</em><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com/viewpoint-dilemma-underpaid-adjunct/">VIEWPOINT: The Dilemma of the Underpaid Adjunct</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.thehoya.com"></a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thehoya.com/viewpoint-dilemma-underpaid-adjunct/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
